孤独之夜
Lonesome night.
婴孩恸哭  寒风刺骨
Rabbits bawlin', wind bitin' the bone.
风中夹杂着
Wind like this
千万种声音
full of voices.
那是祖先
Ancestry howlin' at you,
诉说远古的故事
yibberin' stories.
所有声音
All voices
汇聚为一
tied up into one.
但有一个声音
One voice different.
与众不同
One voice,
在黑暗中觊觎
whisperin' out there,
窃窃私语
spyin' from the dark.
那是青面獠牙的魔鬼
That fangy devil,
老乔治
Ol' Georgie himself.
靠过来  仔细听
Now you hear up close,
我要给你们讲讲我和他第一次
and I'll yarn you about the first time we met,
四目相对的时刻
eye to eye.
于是我见到了亨利·古斯医生
And thus it was when I made the acquaintance of Dr. Henry Goose,
期望他能将我从痛苦中解救出来
the man I hoped might cure me of my afflictions.
你丢了什么吗
Have you lost something?
问题一
Question one.
思科史密斯的报告里有什么秘密
What secret in Sixsmith report
竟招来杀身之祸
would be worth killing for?
问题二
Question two.
是不是可以认为
Is it reasonable to believe
他们为了掩盖秘密会再开杀戒
that they would kill again to protect that secret?
如果是的话  第三个问题
And if so, question three.
我他妈的在这干什么
What the fuck am I doing here?
作为一个经验丰富的编辑
While my extensive experience as an editor
我是不屑用闪回
has lead me to a disdain for flashbacks
或是倒叙这种花哨的技巧的
and flash forwards, and all such tricksy gimmicks,
然而  亲爱的读者
I believe that if you, dear reader,
我还是希望您耐心一点
can extend your patience for a just a moment,
从我这疯狂的故事中理出头绪来
you will find there is a method to this tale of madness.
《云图六重奏》  作者：罗伯特·弗洛比舍
亲爱的思科史密斯
My dearest Sixsmith,
今早我用维维安·艾瑞斯的手枪
I shot myself through the roof of my mouth this morning,
饮弹自尽
with Vyvyan Ayrs' Luger.
真正的自杀是一场深思熟虑的谋划
A true suicide is a paced, disciplined certainty.
人们断言  自杀系懦夫之为
People pontificate "Suicide is an coward's act".
事实却是大相径庭
Couldn't be further from the truth.
自杀需要极大的勇气
Suicide takes tremendous courage.
有任何情况请按这个按钮
Any problem, sir, you just hit this button.
谢谢
Thank you.
我代表本部门以及统一体的未来
On behalf of my Ministry, and the future of Unanimity,
感谢您接受最后一次审讯
I would like to thank you for this final interview.
叫停核反应堆
不要让核反应堆害死我们
-你好  -媒体通行证
- Hello. - Press pass.
媒体通行证
以为我是找麻烦的吗
Expecting trouble?
我只是德蒙特·霍金斯的出版商
I was Dermot Hoggins' publisher,
又不是他的心理咨询师  或是算命的
not his shrink or his astrologer,
所以我确确实实没想到
and the ruddy, bloody truth is,
他那天晚上会干出那种事
I had no idea what the man was gonna do that night.
这片沙滩曾经是食人族
This beach was once a cannibal's banqueting hall,
吃掉弱者的地方
where the strong gorged on the weak,
但是他们会吐出牙齿
but the teeth, sir, they spat out,
就像我们吐樱桃核一样
like you and I would expel a cherry stone.
你知道一磅牙齿能卖多少钱吗
Do you know the price a quarter pound of these will earn?
这并非是质问或是审判
Remember this is not an interrogation or a trial.
我们只要你描述事实
Your version of the truth is all that matters.
事实只有一个
Truth is singular.
主观的描述  都不是事实
Its "versions" are mistruths.
不要告诉他们我是为情自尽的
Don't let them say I killed myself for love.
我的确对其他人动过心 但天地你我皆知
Had my infatuations, but we both know in our hearts
在我昙花一现的生命中  你是我唯一的挚爱
who is the sole love of my short, bright life.
好了  尤因先生
There you are, Mr. Ewing,
不信教的地方
as binding a covenant there can ever be between men
就是这么签订契约的
outside the province of Scripture.
谢谢你  霍洛牧师
Thank you, Reverend Horrox,
我想我岳父听了一定欣喜若狂
I know my father-in-law is profoundly excited about this deal.
汉斯科尔·摩尔是一位伟人
Haskell Moore is a great man.
未来靠的就是他这种人
Future generations depend on men like him,
敢于直话直说
men capable of speaking the truth.
确实如此
Quite.
第一次看汉斯科尔·摩尔的作品时
When I first encountered
我赞叹不已
Haskell Moore's writing,
他的文字简明而有力度
its perspicuity stroke me
犹如神旨天降
as though delivered through divine revelation.
这位博学的医生和我
The learned doctor here and I,
经常在晚上 研究讨论他的文章
already spent many a night debating Mr. Moore's tractus.
我倒想听听他如何解释
I'm only willing to conceive that he makes a compelling case
为何我们能坐下来  大快朵颐
as to why we are sitting here, enjoying this divine lamb,
库巴卡却要站在一旁  听候差遣
while Kupaka stands there, contempt to serve.
可不是吗  库巴卡
Indeed, ain'it. Kupaka,
你在这里过的挺自在的  对吧
you enjoy your life here with us, do you not?
先生  那是当然
Yes, Reverend, sir.
库巴卡很开心
Kupaka very happy here.
看吧  这就是摩尔的文明梯度理论
See, you see, this is Moore's ladder of civilization.
之所以会这样是因为
The reason behind this natural order...
好了  吉尔斯  闭嘴吧
Please, Giles, do shut up.
听你说了几个星期了
I've been listening to this for weeks,
来听听他自己女婿的看法
I would love to know what his own son-in-law has to say about it.
好吧
Let's see.
我认为  这是出于神的旨意和男人的天性
It is an inquiry concerning God's will and the nature of men.
那他对女人的天性有何看法
And what does he have to say about the nature of women?
恐怕他回避了这一问题
I'm afraid that's a subject he prefers to pass by in silence.
男人都这德行
He wouldn't be the first.
好了  继续吧
Prey, Mr. Ewing, continue.
他关注的问题是
The question he does pose is
如果神是造物主
if God created the world,
那我们如何判断 哪些事物我们可以改变
how do we know what things we can change,
哪些又神圣不可侵犯呢
and what things must remain sacred and inviolable?
霍洛牧师相信  管理殖民地最好的方法
Reverend Horrox' real specific how to run plantation.
就是乔治亚州的方法
Georgian way best way he say.
天啊  这么炎热的天
God, this heat is unbearable.
他们怎么受得了
How do they take it?
霍洛牧师说
Reverend Horrox say
奴隶如骆驼  生养于沙漠
slaves like camel, bred for desert.
他们并非文明人 是感觉不到炎热的
He say they not feel heat like civilized folk.
我们找个地方乘凉吧
Now we should get you out of the sun.
那是什么声音
Now what is that noise?
-你醒了  -发生了什么事
- There you are. - What happened?
跟我猜的一样  寄生虫惹的祸
It is as I suspected. Gusano Coco Cervello,
波利尼西亚蛆虫
better known as the Polynesian worm.
我见过生这种病
Once saw a man's brain
死掉的人 大脑像花椰菜一样
after the worm had finished with him maggoty cauliflower.
不过别担心
But have no fear,
我和这小魔鬼已经是老相识了
this particular devil and I are well acquainted.
吞下去  好了好了  没事了
Here we go. Yes, yes, all gone.
真不敢想要是没遇见你
I don't know what I would have done
我会怎么样
had our paths not crossed.
最起码你是活不成了
Well, for starters, you would have died.
我得报答你的恩情
I shall find a way to repay you.
没必要  真的
Unnecessary, I assure you.
我可是医生  亚当
I am a doctor, Adam.
这叫做江山易改  本性难移
A tiger cannot change its stripes.
思科史密斯
Sixsmith,
我恳请你原谅我
I do hope you will be able to find it in your heart to forgive me.
弗洛比舍先生
Mr. Frobisher.
罗伯特·弗洛比舍先生
Mr. Robert Frobisher!
我们经理想要和您谈一谈  先生
The management would like a word with you, please, sir.
弗洛比舍先生  请开门
Mr. Frobisher, open this door, please!
我知道你在里面  请开开门
I do know you're in there, Mr. Frobisher, please, comply.
我们已经写信给您父亲了
A letter is being drafted to your father, sir.
弗洛比舍先生
Mr. Frobisher!
我不愿这样离开你
Hated leaving you like that.
不想以这种方式告别
Wasn't the goodbye I had in mind.
你读这封信时
By the time you read this,
我已启程去往爱丁堡
I will be on my way to Edinburgh,
去追求名与利
on my way to fame and fortune.
我想你没听说过维维安·艾瑞斯
I know you haven't heard of him,
但相信我
but trust me,
他可是位音乐巨匠
Vyvyan Ayrs is one of the musical greats, Sixsmith.
只可惜因为常年病痛
The tragedy is that he hasn't produced any new work
很久没有新作了
in years due to illness.
我打算说服他 让我做他的抄谱员
My scheme is to persuade him to hire me as his amanuensis,
协助他再创辉煌
and aid him in the creation of a masterpiece,
登上音乐界的巅峰
before shooting up through the musical firmament,
最终帕特就不得不承认
eventually obliging Pater to admit that yes,
他剥夺了继承权的儿子  罗伯特·弗洛比舍
the son he disinherited is none other than Robert Frobisher,
成为了当代最杰出的作曲家
the greatest British composer of his time.
思科史密斯  你现在一定在摇头叹息
I know, Sixsmith, you groan and shake your head,
可是你一定也在微笑
but you smile too,
我爱的就是这点
which is why I love you.
附
P.S.
谢谢你的马甲
Thanks for the waistcoat.
我需要有你的物品陪在身边
I needed something of yours to keep me company.
圣乔治与龙
St. George and the Dragon.
它提醒我作曲就像战斗
Reminds me that composing is a crusade.
人龙之争
Sometimes you slay the dragon,
必定是你死我活
sometimes the dragon slays you.
好了
Alright, then.
弗洛比舍  是吧
Frobisher, is it?
听了马克拉斯的交代  你应该能干点活了
I trust Mackerras told you enough to be useful.
这几个月  我脑海中
I've had this little melody for viola
都回响着一段中提琴旋律
rattling about my head for months,
看你能不能把它记下来
let's see if you can get it down.
第3小节前加装饰音
Subtle grace note before the third.
轻柔而简洁  明白不
Soft and simple. Got it?
接下来才是好戏
Now, it gets interesting.
好
Good.
从头弹一遍
Play that back.
是  先生
Would love to, sir.
请问是什么调呢
What key are we in?
这还用问吗  当然是G小调
What key? G minor, of course.
拍号呢
And the time signature?
天呐  你刚听什么了
For Christ's sake, did you hear it or not?
请再给我一点时间
Just need a little more time.
你说要时间
You need?
到底谁才是打工的
My dear boy, who is working for whom here?
很抱歉  先生
I apologize, sir.
你是来抄谱还是来道歉的
Are you an amanuensis or an apologist?
集中精神
Now pay attention.
4分之3拍
Three-four,
在第4小节转到4分之4拍
changes to four-four on fourth bar
在第5小节转到4分之3拍
and back to three-four on bar five,
数数你还是会的吧
if you can count that high.
四分音符dor 停一个八音符
Crotchet G, pause for a quaver,
重复八分音符dor
repeat G quaver,
然后在重拍时降mi
then E-flat on the down beat.
然后反复
And so on.
弹来听听
Alright, let me hear you.
停  求你了  折磨死我了
Stop, please! You're hurting me!
你没听错吧
You must have misheard me,
我嘴里的旋律被你弹成了垃圾
I said I had a melody not a malady!
维维安
Vyvyan.
乔科斯塔  扶我回房
Jocasta, deliver me!
你们在做什么
What's going on in here?
在浪费时间
An exercise in futility.
是不是该介绍一下呢
Should I be introduced?
没必要
There's really no point,
这孩子就是个花瓶
the boy is useful as the clap.
幸好不像花柳那么难缠
Fortunately, he'll be much easier to get rid of.
帮个忙  叫亨利来送他出去
Would you be a dear and get Henry to show the boy out.
没问题  亲爱的
Yes, of course, darling.
那简直是天籁
That's beautiful.
是啊
Yes.
这就是我心里的旋律
That's it. That's my melody!
别这样嘛  路易莎  我们是天生一对
Com'on, Luisa, we're made to be together!
听我说  路易莎
Luisa, Luisa, com'on, com'on, I'm telling you,
宝贝  你不能离开我
I'm telling you baby, you can't leave me. It's a...
不知道是前世还是未来
Don't know if it's a past life thing or a future life thing,
我和你
but you know, you and me...
整整一个小时
Look. For the last hour,
我都忍着不把你扔下楼去
all I could think about was throwing you off the balcony.
你以为你是哪根葱啊
Well then who the hell you think you are?
给垃圾专栏写几句垃圾有什么牛的
You write a bullshit column for a fucking rag.
等一下
Elevator!
谢谢
Thank you.
有个从骑士时代来的人真好
Nice to know the age of chivalry isn't dead.
你还好吗
You okay?
估计骨头没断
No bones broken, I think.
不  您别动  我来
No, no, no, you sit yourself. Let me see.
好极了  停电
Great. Power outage.
真是雪上加霜
Perfect end to a perfect day.
还觉得我给你开门是好事吗
Still glad the age of chivalry isn't dead?
我宁愿困在这儿
I'd still rather be right here
也不要回去
than back up there.
看来齐平先生不是人见人爱
Guess Mr. Kipin isn't everyone's cup of tea.
他是记者的噩梦
Guys like that are just an occupational hazard.
你在采访他吗
You were interviewing him?
没错  我来自《望远镜》杂志
Yeah, for Spyglass magazine.
叫路易莎·雷
Luisa Rey.
我是卢夫斯·思科史密斯
Rufus Sixsmith.
雷
Rey.
莫非你和记者莱斯特·雷有亲戚
You wouldn't happen to be related to the journalist Lester Rey?
他是我父亲
Yeah. He was my father.
真的吗  他要是看到女承父业
Really? He must have been enormously proud of you,
一定会为你自豪的
following in his footsteps.
这是我侄女  梅根
That's her. My niece, Megan.
真可爱
She's lovely!
天生的物理学家
Born physicist,
数学能力比我强多了
with a better mind for mathematics than I ever had.
在剑桥凯斯学院
Did her PhD at Cambridge,
修了博士学位
a woman at Caius!
让我觉得世界还是美好的
Gives you hope for the world.
热死了
It's hot.
而且还困在这里
And we're still here.
那是个很独特的胎记
That's a very peculiar birthmark.
是啊  我的小彗星
Yeah. My little comet.
我妈说那是癌症
My mother was sure it was cancer,
想方设法让我把它去掉  但是
She wanted me to get it removed, but...
我还挺喜欢它的
don't know. I kinda like it.
我认识一个人
I knew someone who had a birthmark that was...
他也有一模一样的胎记
similar to that.
真的假的
Really?
那是谁
Who was it?
我非常爱的一个人
Someone I cared about very much.
问你一个问题  雷小姐
A hypothetical question for you, Miss Rey.
作为一名记者
As a journalist,
为了保护消息来源 你愿意付出什么代价
what price would you pay to protect the source?
一切代价
Any.
牢狱之灾呢
Prison?
万不得已的话  也愿意
If it came to that, yes.
你愿意冒生命危险吗
Would you be prepared to compromise your safety?
我父亲刚正不阿
My father braved booby-trapped marshes
即使受强权威胁  也从不退缩
and the wrath of generals for his journalistic integrity.
如果稍有危险  我就畏缩不前
What kind of daughter would I be
不是丢了他的脸
if I bailed when things got a little tough?
得救了
Saved.
出租车
Taxi!
真的不搭车吗
You sure you don't need a cab?
不了  我自己开车来的
No, I've got my car.
如果你需要我帮忙
Well, you know if there's ever something I can do for you,
就打给我吧
please give me a call.
谢谢  我会的
Thank you, I will.
再见
Bye.
那晚是柠檬奖的庆祝宴会
It was the night of the Lemon Prizes,
虽然一晚上都在强颜欢笑
and amidst all that forced jollity,
但有那么一刻  我是在自省
I recall a moment of introspection.
选择做出版商  真是我这辈子
Why? Why would anyone in their right mind
最没脑子的决定
choose to be a publisher?
也就在那一刻 德蒙特找到了我
This was the precise moment that Dermot found me.
-蒂莫西  -德蒙特
- Timothy. - Dermot.
糟糕透顶了
Bad news inexorably does.
真他妈浪费
Fockin' waste.
赫尔曼·梅尔维尔生前写过一本
Never forget Herman Melville,
关于一条大白鲸的书[也就是《白鲸》]
writes a ripping yarn about a big white whale
当时也被大家忽视了
which is summarily dismissed,
然而今天
and yet today,
世界上每个文学学生
it is lugged around in the backpacks
都随身带着这本书
of every serious student of literature in the world.
我他妈不在乎我死后的事
I don't give a fock what happens when I'm dead,
我要他们现在就买老子的书
I want people to buy me book now!
作为这本书的发行人
As your publisher,
这当然也是我乐意看到的
obviously nothing would make me happier.
可惜  不知道是什么原因
But sadly, for whatever reason,
读者还没能理解《老拳夹击》
"Knuckle Sandwich" has yet to connect to its audience.
想知道原因吗
You want a reason?
我这就让你知道
I'll give you a reason.
-他就是原因  -你说芬奇先生吗
- Right there! - Aah. You mean Mr. Finch?
狗娘养的菲力·芬奇
Felix fockin' Finch!
在他那本娘娘腔杂志上
That cunt that shat all over me book
把我的书贬得像一坨狗屎
in his poncy fockin' magazine!
-没那么糟糕  -你说没那么糟
- It wasn't that bad! - No?
霍金斯这本自吹自擂的自传
"Mr. Hoggins should apologize to the trees
完全是浪费纸张  他应该向树木道歉
failed for the making of his bloated autobio novel.
一个索然无味的结尾
Four hundred vain-glorious pages expire in an ending
居然占了整整400页纸
that is flat and inane beyond belief."
冷静点  德蒙特
Steady now, Dermot.
评论家看书都是一扫而过
What is a critic but one who reads quickly,
自以为是  却从来不动脑子
arrogantly, but never wisely.
我操
Fock it.
德蒙特
Dermot!
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen!
各位同行  今晚有一个追加的特别奖项
We have an additional award tonight, fellow book faeries.
最杰出评论家奖
An award for "Most eminent critic".
就是这个
Mr...
不对  应该是
oh, beg pardon,
菲力·芬奇爵士  大英帝国勋章获得者
SIR! Felix Finch. O, B and E!
那请问奖励呢
And what might my prize be, I wonder?
送你一本还没变成废纸的签名版《老拳夹击》
A signed copy of an unpulped "Knuckle Sandwich"?
你的书基本上都是废纸吧
Can't be many of those left.
好吧
Well.
现在让我们看看
Just what does that lead-less pencil
你怎么用所谓的想象力
you call an imagination have in mind
结束这尴尬的一幕
to end this scene.
这种结局你应该会喜欢
I think you're gonna love this one.
这个结尾有味道吧
Now, that's an ending that is flat n'inane beyond belief.
你问我的想法
My thoughts?
说实话  我的惊恐像芬奇一样
If I'm honest, I admit that the obvious emotions like shock
一闪而过
and horror flew as Finch had, here and gone.
龙舌兰  这么多
Tequila, couple of fingers.
目睹这悲剧的一幕后
While deep down,
尽管我的心沉到了谷底
I experienced a nascent sense
一种绝处逢生的感觉却油然而生
of a silver lining to this most tragic turn.
一夜之间
Overnight,
"灰头土脸"德蒙特成了万人敬仰的大英雄
Dermot "Dusty" Hoggins became a cult hero to the common man.
作家1:0评论家
评论家晚宴遇袭身亡
甩你几条街  霍金斯送芬奇自由飞翔
《老拳夹击》
"Knuckle Sandwich"
两个月内狂售9万本
shifted 90000 copies in less than two months.
《老拳夹击》
我仿佛变成了灰姑娘
I was for the briefest of moments, Cinderella,
美梦成真后
and all memory of past misfortune receded
过去的不幸逐渐消逝
in the rearview mirror of my dream come true.
-我的娘啊  -蒂莫西还是什么来着
- What the fuck... - Tim-o-tee Cavendish... oy presume.
屎料未及吧
Caught wi' your cacks down!
我的工作时间是11点到下午2点
My office hours are eleven to two,
希望你们遵守程序
and my secretary would be more than happy
跟我的秘书预约一下
to schedule an appointment if you so desire.
我们那么熟  哪儿还要预约
Friends like us don't need appointments.
我们就是这么随便
We like it all cozy like this.
我们去探望了一下德蒙特
Visited Dermot in the joint.
他有事要问你
Our brother's got a question for you.
我们那份钱呢
Where's our focking money?
伙计们  我跟你们说
Boys. Boys, look here.
德蒙特签了一份版权转让合同
Dermot signed what we call a copyright transfer contract,
上面写明...
which means that legally...
德蒙特才没有签那狗屁合同
Dermot didn't sign a fockin' contract for the event of a season!
那或许我们可以友好协商一下
Perhap-perhaps... er, we could moot a provisional sum
分一部分钱出来
as a basis for on-going negotiation.
好呀
Okey dokey.
一部分钱是多少钱
What sum we gonna moot?
最少5万
Fifty K will do for starters.
5万挺合理的
Fifty sounds reasonable.
明天下午前给我们
Tomorrow afternoon.
明天下午
Tomorrow afternoon?
要现金  少废话
Cash.  No bullocks.
-不要支票  -只收纸钞
- No checks. - Old fashioned money.
先生们
Gentlemen.
-法律规定  -法律
- The law says... - The law?!
法律为他妈的菲力·芬奇做什么了吗
What'd the law do for Felix fockin' Finch?
通常
Ordinarily,
我会先让犯人回忆早期的记忆
I begin by asking prisoners to recall their earliest memories
统一体
给未来的历史学家
to provide a context
提供研究材料
for the corporatic historians of the future.
人造人并没有这种记忆  先生
Fabricants have no such memories, Archivist.
我们在宋老爹餐厅的每一天
One twenty-four hour cycle in Papa Song's
都是一模一样的
is identical to every other.
你的通用语说的很好
May I say you speak Consumer surprisingly well.
可惜统一体的政府官员
It is unfortunate that the officials of the Unanimity
只能说一种语言
can only speak one language.
作为统一体的政府人员
As an officer of Unanimity,
我当然只能说这一种语言
I am of course restricted from using sub speak.
我看也是
Of course.
请详细描述宋老爹餐厅24小时的运作
Please describe a typical twenty-four hour Papa Song cycle.
早上4点  所有人会被刺激素唤醒
At hour four, each server is woken by auto-stimulin.
星美-451
然后前往清洗室
From revival, we proceed to the hygiener.
穿好衣服后  排队进入餐厅
After dressing, we file into the dinery.
5点钟
At hour five,
我们各自就位 开始服务客人
we man our stations to greet the new day's consumers.
欢迎光临宋老爹餐厅
Welcome to Papa Song's.
接下来的19个小时
For the next nineteen hours,
我们负责下单  送餐  续杯
we input orders, tray food, vend drinks,
加调料  擦桌子  倒垃圾
upstock condiments, wipe tables, and bin garbage,
一切都严格遵循第一准则
all done in strict adherence to First Catechism.
什么是第一准则
What is the First Catechism?
顾客就是上帝
"Honor Thy Consumer."
收拾完后
After the final cleaning,
我们摄入一袋汤食 然后返回睡眠舱
we imbibe one soap sack and return to our sleep box.
这就是每天的流程
That is the blueprint of every single day.
你曾经想过未来吗
Did you ever think about the future?
宋老爹的服务员 只有一种可能的未来
Papa Song servers have just one possible future.
你是说极乐
You mean "Exultation".
你能描述一下这一年一度的仪式吗
Could you describe this annual Rite of Passage?
每年第一天
On first day,
李总管 在每个人的颈圈上打星号
Seer Rhee would stamp a star on each of our collars.
十二颗星代表契约期满
Twelve stars meant an end to our contract.
当你看到有姐妹进入极乐了  有什么感觉
How did you feel when you watched one of your sisters ascend?
兴奋
Excitement.
我为她们高兴
I was happy for them,
但同时也很嫉妒
but envious as well.
你的姐妹们也有同感吗
Did your sister servers feel as you did?
不全是
Most of them.
我想听下声名狼藉的育娜-939的事情
I would like to ask about the infamous Yoona-939.
星美-451
育娜-939唤醒了你
If Yoona-939 woke you,
那谁唤醒了她
who woke her?
李总管
Seer Rhee.
总管为什么要唤醒服务员
Why would Seer wake a server?
档案员  或许你应该问他
Perhaps you should ask him, Archivist.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
他喝了汤食
He drinks soap.
这让他很快乐
It makes him happy.
然后他就像我们一样酣睡了
Then he sleep like us in our box.
你曾经想过...
Do you ever think about...
服务员到了那边
what it must be like,
是什么样子吗
up there with the consumers?
第三本手册禁止这种问题
Third Catechism forbids such questions.
是的  是禁止
Yes. It does.
来吧  给你看个秘密
Come. Let me show you a secret.
四号平台
Platform four,
失物招领
Lost and Found.
现在...星美
Now... Sonmia,
这就是我们的秘密
we are inside a secret.
视频播放器
A Kino?
-这是不行的  -星美  不会有人知道的
- We are not allowed. - Sonmia, No one will ever know.
来吧
Come.
这违反了监禁法案
This is a violation of the ruddy Incarceration Act!
我不会向暴力犯罪行为屈服
I will not be subjugated to criminal abuse.
这违反了监禁法案
This is a violation of the ruddy Incarceration Act!
我不会向暴力犯罪行为屈服
I will not be subjugated to criminal abuse.
你可能会被剔除
You could have been excised.
你为何要冒这个险
How did you justify such a risk to yourself?
她是我的朋友
She was my friend.
请从你的视角
Please describe the events of September 18th
描述9月18日的事件
from your perspective.
我被安排在一号台服务
I was stationed at pedestal one.
-快去吧  -秀两手
- Come on, do it. - Yeah, do it.
我不会向暴力犯罪行为屈服
I will not be subjugated to criminal abuse!
退后
Step away.
黄色警戒
Code yellow,
该区域安全
the area is secured.
夏威夷群岛  末日后第106个冬季
这生活失去了微笑  充满了无趣
Nay, this life all rot n' lockin' no smile a' some yawnee.
在后来的日子里
In rear's time,
我一直保守司露莎圣徒的秘密
I ever fest the secret of Sloosha's hallow.
亚当  我的妹夫
Adam, my bro' by law,
带着儿子从霍诺卡市场跋涉回来
n' his son n' me been trekkin' back from Honokaa Market.
亚当像往常一样
It was Adam's custom to cult out his ancestry
心怀敬畏祭祀祖先
with offerin's n' honorin's.
突然间
Suddenwise,
那个青面獠牙的恶魔
that fangy devil's eyes,
我感觉到了
I felt'em.
谁在那里
Who there?
朋友  你这个位置很不好
a darky spot you're in, friend.
老乔治
Ol' Georgie...
在事实面前你无处可藏
Ain't no blade can protect you from the True-True.
爸爸
'Pa!
乔纳斯  乔纳斯  快跑  快跑  快跑
Jonas. Jonas, go. Go, go!
扎克里  扎克里
Zachary! Zachary?
扎克里
Zachary!!
待在这里  这里安全...
Stay here, safe here...
扎克里
Zachary!!
日落时刻  科纳将享用亚当和他儿子
Kona will be feastin' on Adam n' his boy by sundown.
扎克里
Zachary!!
扎克里  扎克里
Zachary!! Zachary!!
你不是一直在说吗
You say it all the time, ain'ya?
弱肉强食
"The Weak are Meat, the Strong do Eat."
乔纳斯  不要
Jonas, no!
真相就是如此
The True-truth, what that is.
整个山谷都在传言
Whole valley whisperin' about
是我害死了亚当和他的儿子
the blood o' Adam and his son on my hands.
但罗斯和凯金从不相信这些谣言
But Rose and Catkin never believed those rumors,
一直支持我
and stood by me.
-扎克叔叔  快看  -我看到了
- Uncle Zach, look! - Yeah, I see them.
先知们每年两次来交换物品
Prescients come batterin' twice a year,
他们的飞船远赴重洋
their ships creep-crawlin' on the waves,
靠末世之前的科技前行
just floatin' on the Smart o' the Old Uns.
交易马上就要开始了
Barter'll be startin' soon.
是啊  去找你妈妈吧
Yeah. We must go find ya' Ma.
你怎么了
What are you doin'?
妈妈说自从司露莎的事后你就不对劲
Ma says ya ain't been right since Sloosha's.
她说我们要多关心你
She say we gotta keep out our eyes on ya.
你照顾我  我照顾羊  是吗
You mindin' me, while I mind the goats?
我知道了
I see.
问题是  谁在交易时照顾你妈妈呢
Stump is, who's gonna mind your Ma at the Barter?
她不像我们两个会砍价
She got no tongue for hagglin', not like you and me.
她能搞定的
She doin' alright.
绝对可以  回家吃晚饭吧
Swear by. Be home for suppin'.
为什么需要讲话时  却张口结舌
Why words slink n' slide off a tongue, when we need them most?
如果我的舌头更大胆点
If my tongue'd been more bold,
是不是就可以阻止将要发生的灾难
could I have stopped all that diresome's about to happen?
-扎克叔叔  -这是我哥哥  跟你讲过的
- Uncle Zach! - Thi's my big bro I yawned you about.
妹妹  怎么回事
What's about, sis?
招待贵宾
Special guest hosting.
谢谢你在交易日的盛情款待
Thank you for the kindsome hostin' in the Valley's day.
罗斯  我可没答应
I ain't saysoe this, Rose.
女祭司说这是无上荣耀
Abbess saysoe a gift of great honor.
那让她招待去吧
She can be hostin' then?
扎克里  我给你带了礼物
I brin' you gift, Zachry.
我不要陌生人的礼物
Need no gift from the stranger.
现在不论是兄弟  还是不熟的人
Now kin n' bros n' half-strangers,
甚至是女祭司  都来拜访
yay, even the Abbess, they all come knockin',
他们好奇心十足地看着
they gaped in wonderment
仿佛星美现身了一样
like Sonmi herself was sittin' in our kitchen.
先知们的飞船
Questions about Prescience
为什么那么快
n' their whoahsome Ship poured thick n'fast.
你们的飞船怎么能无声地滑翔
How your ship's slidin', glides so silent n'...
融合引擎
Fusion engines.
没人问融合引擎是什么
No one queried what fusion engine was,
因为不想让人觉得自己愚蠢
cos they didn't want to look stupid in front o' the gatherin'.
融合引擎
Fusion engines...
的确  梅洛内回答了不少问题
True really was, Meronym answered the questions,
但依然浇不灭大家的好奇心
but no answer ever quenched your curio.
她回答得越多  大家越不相信她
All o' that answerin' done was teach everyone to not trust her,
哪怕是一点点
nay, not a flea...
她在说谎
She's lyin'....
密谋着想先融入这里
Schemin' and wormin' herself in.
看住她  看紧她
Watch her, watch her close.
她有秘密
She's got secrets.
扎克里·贝里
Zachry Bailey?
很抱歉吵醒您但是  做了噩梦
Sorrysome for wakin' you up but... A dream.
有可怕的事将要发生
Some diresome's gonna happen.
进来  进来
Come in, come in.
那个星美抓住了你的心
that Sonmi got your heart.
让我来听一听
I gonna hear it for us,
我为你祈祷
I'm prayin' for you.
老乔治渴望你的灵魂
Old Georgie's hungerin' for your soul.
我知道
I knew it.
诅咒了你的梦
- Spit a cuss on your dreams.   - XXXXX
桥之将断藏下头
"Bridge is broken, hide below"
双手流血勿松手
"Hands are bleedin', can't let go"
敌人酣睡莫割喉
"Enemy's sleepin', don't slit that throat"
预言
An augurin'...
扎克里
Zachary.
信任星美
Trust Sonmi...
记住给你的警示
Keep her warnin' with you,
刻在脑海里
nail it to your memory.
谢谢  谢谢  女祭司  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you, Abbess. Thank you.
星美-451
Sonmi 451.
等等  等等
Wait! Wait.
不用躲着我
There's... no reason to hide.
我知道你  星美-451
I know you are... Sonmi-451.
我叫张海柱
My name is... Hae-Ju Zheng.
李总管怎么了
What has happened to Seer Rhee?
汤食过量
Soap overdose.
很不幸
It is unfortunate
事业正盛时遭遇这种事
that it had to happen with everything gone so well.
因为现在执法者
Cos now it is probable that the Enforcers
和DNA嗅探器很可能会发现你
and the DNA sniffers will find out about you.
如果他们查到你...
And if they do...
如果他们意识到你和育娜-939的关系
if they realize your connection to Yoona-939,
你就会被剔除
you will be excised.
但你可以选择
But you have a choice.
留在这里  冒着被查到的风险
You can remain here and risk being discovered,
或者和我一起走
or you can come with me.
改变航道  伙计们
Bear away, boy.
遵命  船长
Aye, aye captain.
15号周五
Friday the 15th.
我们早潮时扬帆起航
We made sail with the morning tide.
波海威先生更改了我的船舱
Mr. Boerhaave had my cabin changed.
让我住在储藏室里
I have been quarantined
与其他乘客和船员隔离
to a store room away from the other passengers and crew.
亨利争论说波利尼西亚蠕虫不传染
Henry argued in vain that the Polynesian worm
但没有用
was not contagious.
这些都无关紧要
Not that it matters.
现在我只想赶紧回家
All I want to do now is return home
好好放松身心
and unburden myself from this responsibility.
《太平洋日记》
亲爱的思科史密斯
My dear Sixsmith,
我非常渴望你的帮助
I am in desperate need of your help.
收到我上一封信后
After my last letter,
你肯定在准备行囊了
I'm sure you're rushing to pack your bags,
但是不要来  真的
but you needn't, really.
当然
Unless of course,
除非你希望亲眼目睹罗伯特·弗洛比舍的重生
you wish to witness the rebirth of Robert Frobisher.
真神奇
Is it not miraculous
人的运势 可以转变得这么快
how one's fortune can turn so quickly,
这么彻底
so completely.
前一刻还狼狈的跳窗而逃
One moment, leaping from a hotel window,
下一刻就荣幸地被世界上
the next gainfully employed
最伟大的作曲家之一雇用
by one of the world's greatest living composers.
《太平洋日记》
唯一的困扰是机缘巧合  我迷上了一本日记
My only problem is that I accidentally got hooked on a journal
是一个濒死的律师在1849年
written in 1849 by a dying lawyer during the voyage
从太平洋岛屿到旧金山时写的
from the Pacific islands to San Francisco.
可是日记只有前半本
To my great annoyance, the pages cease mid-sentence.
后半本找不到
Half the book is missing.
但我非常着迷
It's completely getting me.
方便的话  下次去奥拓书店买书时
Could you be a mensch and when you're next foraging
帮忙问一下
at Otto's Book's, make an inquiry?
毕竟一本不完整的书
A half finished book is, after all,
就像一段不完整的情缘
a half finished love affair.
美国爱石油
America loves oil.
美国已经对石油上瘾了
America is addicted to oil.
有些人幻想用风能和沼气来替代
Some fantasize about wind turbines or peat gas.
天鹅颈  核能集团
但我在这里要告诉你们
But I'm here today to tell you that the cure
解决的方法在这里
for oil is right here.
就是核能
The cure is nuclear power.
就是天鹅颈
The cure is Swannekke.
天鹅颈水合反应堆
你好
Hello?
你好  雷小姐
Hello, Miss Rey.
很抱歉在这个时间打扰你
I'm frightfully sorry for calling you at this hour.
思科史密斯博士
Dr. Sixsmith?
我需要帮助
I need help.
我需要50000英镑
I need 50,000 pounds,
不是2000  是50000
not 2,000, 50,000!
我重新核对了一遍  卡文迪许先生
I'm going through it again, Mr. Cavendish,
但总数是对的
but the total's right.
就是2343英镑16便士
2,343 pounds and 16 pence.
怎么可能  我可是赚了一大把
How is this possible? The ruddy money was pouring in.
主要用于还债了  卡文迪许先生
Debts mostly, Mr. Cavendish.
主动还债也是有弊端的
Solvency has its drawbacks.
情况看起来很糟糕
The situation looked dire,
但我蒂莫西·卡文迪许在这的资本
but I knew that Timothy Cavendish's capital in this town
可不是几个数字能体现的
could not be defined by an accountant's balance sheet!
麦克拉斯基
McCluskie!
你家可爱的小孙子孙女怎么样了
Look, how are those delightful kiddies of yours?
亲爱的  我是"贪婪的卡文迪许"
Mon cher, tis "Cavendish the Ravenous,"
你最爱的蒂莫西
Your favorite Timothy.
亲爱的先生
Mon cher?
你没听错
You heard it correctly,
狄更斯写作的桌子 60000镑出售
Charles Dickens' own original authentic writing desk for £ 60,000.
我认为价格很公道
I think that's very fair.
但我们的记录显示书桌已经
But our records indicate that the desk is already accounted for
由狄更斯博物馆收藏
by the Dickens House Museum.
好吧  那亚瑟·柯南道尔爵士的书桌怎么样
Okay, what about Sir Arthur Conan Doyle's desk?
黑暗中我突然看到了曙光
In the darkness, I suddenly saw the light.
血总归浓于水
Blood has always trumped water.
连霍金斯都找了家人帮忙
If the Hogginses brutes wanted to turn this into a family affair,
我们卡文迪许家族
they'd find the Cavendish Clan
可比他们更厉害
more than ready for the task at hand.
龟孙子的  又来了
Oh, Satan's gonads, not again.
听着 赶紧滚开  让我们清净点
Look, just bugger off and leave us in peace.
我只给你一次机会
I'm only gonna asking you nicely once.
很高兴看到你  丹尼
Good to see you, Denny.
你不把上次还清
I'm not lending you a ruddy farthing
我一毛都不借给你
until you pay back the last lot.
为什么  为什么我要一直帮你
Why-Why should I be forever giving you a hand out?
丹尼...
Denny...
我惹了些不该惹的人
I had a minor running with the wrong sort.
如果拿不出60000英镑
If I don't get my hands on £ 60,000,
我就会被揍惨的
I got to get an awful beating.
让他们录下来发给我  赶紧滚
Well, get them to video it for us, would you? Now fuck off.
丹尼  我不是在开玩笑
I'm not joking, Denholme.
关我什么事
Why is this my problem?
我们是兄弟啊
Because we're brothers!
你不受良心谴责吗
Don't you have a conscience?
吃几片药 再来杯好酒我就没事了
Couple of my special little pills and a G&T should just set me right.
丹尼
Denny.
帮帮我
Help.
求你了
Please.
丹  你在和谁说话
Den, who are you talking to?
你好  乔洁特
Hello, Georgette.
你好  蒂莫西
Hello, Timothy.
好了  好了  好了
Right. Right, right.
60000对吗
What did you-60 grand?
要花点时间  但是...
It's gonna take some time, but, uh...
我先找个好地方让你躲起来吧
in the interim, I've got the perfect place for you to hide.
我开始害怕
I begun to fear
再也不能与深爱的蒂尔达相拥
I might never hold my beloved Tilda in her arms again.
寄生虫在夜间蠕动
My parasite writhes at night,
让我痛苦的痉挛
igniting spasms of pain,
光怪陆离的图像和声音萦绕在周围
while visions and voices, obscene and monstrous, haunt me.
尤因先生...
Mister Ewing...
我的上帝
In the name of God!
尤因先生  不要害怕
Mister Ewing, no fear.
不伤害你  不要叫喊
No harm, not shout.
求你了  我叫奥图阿
Please. My name Autua.
你见过我...
You know I...
看到莫里奥里人鞭打我...
see Moriori whip I...
你见过我
You know I.
你想要什么
What do you want?
你的帮助  尤因先生
You help, Mr. Ewing.
如果你不帮我  我就死定了
If you no help, I in trouble dead.
你已经非常"死定了"
Well, you're already very much "In trouble dead".
女先知号是商船
The Prophetess is a mercantile vessel,
不是偷运奴隶的
not an underground railroad for escaping slaves.
我能做水手  我可以赚船票
I able seaman, I earn passage.
那么我建议你
Well, then I suggest you
去求船长的宽恕吧
surrender to the captain's mercies forthwith.
不不  他们不会听我的
Wow wow. They no hear I.
他们会说"游回家去吧  黑鬼"
They say "Swim away home, nigger",
然后把我扔到海里  而您...
and throw I in drink, but you...
您是律师  对吧  求您
you law man, right? Please.
船长听您的  尤因先生
Captain hear you, Mr. Ewing.
我  我帮不了你
I-I can't help you.
恐怕你要靠你自己了
I'm afraid your fate is entirely your own,
我不想插手
and I desire no part in it.
那么杀了我吧
Then kill I.
别傻了
Don't be absurd...
如果您不帮我
If you no help,
我同样得死 真的
you kill I just the same, is true.
您知道的
You know it.
我不要做鱼食  尤因先生
I'm be no fish food, Mr. Ewing.
死在这里更好
Die here better.
来吧
Do it.
快点下手
Do it quick.
队长  我发现了一个旧路标
I found an old transway marker, Captain.
那里应该就是红山
It's got to be the red mountain.
问题是  山谷里的人害怕它
The problem is, the valley people are afraid of it.
他们认为恶魔住在那里
They think the Devil lives up there.
没人愿意带我穿过科纳领地
I can't find anybody to guide me through the Kona territory.
梅洛内...
Meronym...
多待一天  你的身体就差一点
Every day you're out there, you increase your odd levels.
你的梦想会害死你的  为了什么呢
This dream of yours is going to kill you. And for what?
地外殖民地可能已经不存在了
The Off-World colonies may no longer exist.
队长  我要走了
I got to go, Captain.
谢谢你能来  我在1404
Thank you for coming, I'm in 1404.
我这就上去
I'll be right up.
天鹅颈水合反应堆
思科史密斯博士
Dr. Sixsmith?
是我  路易莎
It's me, Luisa.
打电话  快点  叫警察来
Go call the police. Right now, call the police!
亲爱的思科史密斯
My dear Sixsmith,
只有你 能理解我现在的感受
you alone can understand how I'm feeling right now.
今天  艾瑞斯和我
Today, Ayrs and I
将我们的第一部作品给了塔德斯·凯塞林
presented our first collaboration to Tadeusz Kesselring,
艾瑞斯最喜欢的乐队指挥  来自柏林
Ayrs favorite conductor who arrived from Berlin.
作品叫"永恒的循环"
It's called "Eternal recurrence".
希望你能听听
Wish you could hear it.
这是一战以来
It's the most accomplished tone poem
最精妙的乐章
i know of written since the war,
而且  思科史密斯
and I tell you, Sixsmith,
其中好多旋律都是我的创作
that more than of the few of its best ideas are mine.
在我们那个年代 艾瑞斯
At our time of life, ayrs,
是没人敢如此大胆的创作的
a man has no right to such daring ideas.
看来我这把宝刀
I suppose I've won a rearguard
还不是那么老
action or two in my war against decrepitude.
晚餐是波尔多酒雉鸡  还有奶油乳酪
Diner of pheasant with Bordeaux rich as buttercream.
我很喜欢听不同的人聊天
How I love to listen to men of distinguished lives,
歌唱过去的丑恶与荣耀
sing of past follies and glories.
整个晚上唯一的插曲是
The only broken note in the entire evening
艾瑞斯的妻子  乔科斯塔
was Ayrs wife, Jocasta,
提前离席了
excusing herself early.
感觉有内情
Sensed the buried bone.
后来我问了艾瑞斯
Later I asked Ayrs about it.
他说是凯塞林将乔科斯塔介绍给他的
He said Kesselring had introduced Jocasta to him.
我又打探了一下  凯塞林是否和她相爱过
I pried, had Kesselring been in love with her?
这个问题很麻烦
The subject was a prickly one.
乔科斯塔是犹太人
Jocasta is a Jew.
显然他们之间是不可能的
Obviously her relationship was impossible.
为什么显然
Why obviously?
你不知道德国现在的局势吗
Can you really be so ignorant of what is happening in Germany?
思科史密斯  在这时
At this point in my life,
我才知道
all I know, Sixsmith,
有股力量改变着世界
is that this world spins from the same unseen forces
也扭曲了我们
that twist our hearts.
-扎克里  你好吗  -还可以
- How is it, Mr. Zachry? - Thin whiles.
-介意一起吗  -不介意
- Minding some company? - Nay.
但...
But...
羊和牧人介意  他们脾气可不好
Goats, and so do herders, they're known for housin' temper.
不好意思  你好像介意
Feelin' that own n' your reveal count out,
我突然出现在你家
for invadin' your house with no saysoe.
真的很抱歉
True sorrysome.
现在没关系了
Well it... Now it's done.
你介意陌生人过问你的辉煌史吗
So, you mindin' a stranger coverin' about your thrivin'?
成交  一问换一问
Swap you. Query for query.
好吧
Fair buy.
你不是来学缝衣服和挤牛奶的
Cog you and come dow. Learn stitchin' n' milkin' our heardin'.
你为什么来这里
Why you here?
我需要一个向导
I needin' a guide.
向导  去哪里
Guide? To where?
毛娜索尔
Mauna Sol.
桥之将断藏下头
"Bridge is broken, hide below"
怎么了
What's wrong?
我们一生都回旋在旧日的轨迹中
We cross and recross our old tracks like figure skaters.
就在我读这部新作品时
And just as I was reading a new submission,
《半衰期  一段路易莎·雷迷事》  作者  贾维尔·戈麦兹
一种似曾相识的感觉油然而生
a powerful déjà-vu ran through my bones.
我之前到过那里
I had been there before.
恍如隔世
Another lifetime ago.
乌苏拉
Ursula.
我一生的至爱
The love of my life.
没人比得上她
I could think of no other serious applicants.
她怎么样了
What had happened to her?
更重要的是
And more importantly,
那个也坐在这列车中
what had happened to the young man
为爱人赋词作诗的年轻人
who had ridden the same train composing sonnets,
又怎么样了
to his so bound a love.
女祭司  你的预言应验了
Your augurin' come true, Abbess.
桥断了  像你说的一样
Broke bridge, just like you say.
梅洛内在那里  在她身后
Meronym wa' there, yeb her aback,
《星美-451启示录》  由档案员朴记录
她想去毛娜索尔
trackin' up Mauna Sol,
为什么这个先知给我的生活带来了诅咒
why can this Prescient woman come cursin' n' twistin' on my life?
记住星美的话
Mind the words of Sonmi.
"我们的生命不仅仅属于自己
"Our lives are not our own.
从生到死  我们与他人息息相关
From womb to tomb, we are bound to others.
过去和现在
Past and present.
每一次罪孽...
And by each crime...
以及每一次善行...
and every kindness...
来世都将有报"
rebirth our future."
欢迎来到新首尔
Welcome to Neo Seoul.
来吧  出来吧
Come on, out you come.
这...或许是我这辈子最大的错误
This... maybe the biggest mistake of my life,
- 但是给你  - 尤因先生  谢谢
- but here.   - Thank you, Mr. Ewing.
谢谢
Thank you.
说实话  我担心你饿狠了
Now to tell the truth, I was worried you might try and eat me,
把我吃了
if you didn't get something in the stomach.
尤因先生  你很安全
Oh, you safe, Mr. Ewing.
我不爱吃白肉
I no like white meat.
好吧
Ah. Right.
在我想好怎么帮你前
Before I decide what I'm going to do with you,
能告诉我为什么他们要鞭打你吗
tell me why you were being whipped so savagely?
我叔叔曾是个水手
My uncle was a sailor.
我十岁的时候他把我带上了捕鲸船
He took me on a French whaler when I was ten years old.
见到了世界的精彩
Seen too much of the world.
我不是个好奴隶
I no good slave.
你当时为什么看我
Why did you look at me?
疼痛很强烈  不是吗
Pain strong, right?
但朋友的眼神更强大
Friends eye more strong.
你是个逃跑的奴隶  而我是个律师
Look, you are a runaway slave, and I am a lawyer.
你怎么知道我们能成为朋友
How did you imagine we could possibly be friends?
这就够了
All you need.
天啊
Ah, Jesus!
贾维尔·戈麦兹
Javier Gomez,
不是告诉过你 别跳上我的阳台吗
what did I tell you about jumping onto my balcony?
不想让我进来就不要开着门啊
Why d'you leave the door open if you don't want me to come in?
听着  小机灵鬼
Because, smarty pants,
比跳上阳台更糟糕的事
the only thing worse than having you jumping onto my balcony,
就是看你跳上了窗台
is the idea of you jumping onto my balcony,
却被锁在了外面
and being stuck out there.
好吧
Okay!
你在看什么
What are you reading?
一些旧信件
Old letters.
思科史密斯  剧情在这里走向了肉欲
Sixsmith, the plot has taken a sensual turn.
上周  我和乔科斯塔成为了情人
Last week, Jocasta and I became lovers.
不过不要惊慌
But don't alarm yourself,
我们只是肉体上的  履行职责一样
it is only a carnal act, performed in service,
就好像我是个抄写员一样
not unlike my role as amanuensis.
我承认  女人的心对我来说
And I confess women's hearts
依然很神秘  就像她们的欲望一样
like their desire remain a mystery to me.
事后   她哭着感谢我
Afterward, she cried and thanked me
给他们家重新注入了活力
for bringing life back into their home.
我清楚的感觉到维维安整晚都在我们之间
I can get clear that Vyvyan had been there the entire night,
就好像音符间的休止符一样
between us like the silence between notes,
是通往温馨乐章的钥匙
that holds the key to warm music.
又及  大好消息
P.S: Best news of all,
我开始创作自己的作品了
I've started my own work.
我...想找一张旧唱片
Uh, I... called about an old recording,
作者的名字叫罗伯特·弗洛比舍
written by a man named Robert Frobisher.
找对地方了
Oops. Passed it.
我知道我不应该把它拿出来
I know I shouldn't be pulling it,
就是想检查有没有划坏
I was checking it to make sure it wasn't scratched,
可是  说实话
but... honestly,
我一听就停不下来了
I just can't stop listening to it.
这就是云图六重奏吗
This is the Cloud Atlas Sextet?
罗伯特·弗洛比舍  《云图六重奏》
这就是交响乐
It's... the symphony.
真美
It's beautiful.
不过我觉得我以前听过
But I think I've heard this before.
不会吧
I can't imagine how.
我估计这唱片
I doubt there's no more than a...
全北美也就只有那么几张
handful copies in the whole of North America.
可是我知道它
But I know it.
我知道我听过
I know I know it.
在我意识到之前
Before I realized it,
我的双脚已经把我带回到了祭祀神庙
my feet had brought me back to the Temple of Sacrifice,
在那里  我奉上了我的童贞
where I offered up my virginity.
重回那四日天堂
Back to those four-days of Paradise,
乌苏拉的父母去了希腊
when Ursula's Mater and Pater slift off to Greece,
度周末
for a long weekend...
至少我们以为是这样
Or so we thought.
乌苏拉
Ursula!
衣...衣服
Naked.
先生  女士
Sir! Madam!
我向你们保证 我们只是单纯的...
I assure you this is completely innocent...
双脚踝关节扭伤  一根肋骨骨折
Two sprained ankles, one cracked rib.
病历上的受伤原因写的是
Official cause of accident, listed on hospital form...
也有姑娘、泡妞的意思
猫咪
pussy.
她会不会还住在这里呢
What were the chances that she still lived in this house?
然后  她就出现了
And yet, there she was.
乌苏拉
Ursula.
为什么我从来没有回过她的电话或信件
Why had I never returned her calls or letters?
羞愧  怯懦  卡文迪许家族的特色
Shame, spinelessness, hallmarks of the Cavendish clan.
我意识到我可以选择
I realized I had a choice.
我可以偷偷逃走  继续我的计划
I could slink off and continue as planned,
或者大胆地走进那扇大门
or I could go boldly to the door,
看看我们还有没有希望
and discover what hope, if any, would lay within.
女祭司  快点来  是贝里家的女儿
Abbess, come quick, it's the Bailey girl.
-是凯金吗  -是的  她快死了
- Catkin? - Aye, she dyin'.
-怎...怎么...  -扎克
- What-what... - Zach.
-星美...  -是蝎子鱼
- Sonmi... - It's scorpion fish.
医者说她撑不到日落前
Healer said she be gone by sundown.
不公平  可是无力回天
Ain't right, ain't fair, but nothing to be done.
千万不要动
Be very still.
能杀掉你的东西就在这
Termination charge. Here!
刚好可以炸开颈动脉
Just enough to blow your carotid.
感觉怎么样
How does it feel?
很好
Good.
凯金快死了
Catkin's dying!
-什么  -她不小心踩到了蝎子鱼
- What? - She trod on a scorpion fish.
你能救她
You can save her.
你包里的智能仪器 可以救她
You got spesh smarts in that gearbag, what'll save her.
那是万能药
That's the True-true!
先知委员会的特别指令
Prescient Councils swear by a special order.
要我不能遇事就把自己当做星美女神
Say I can't go play Lady Sonmi for every fate twisty wrong,
乱用机器  招惹是非
and click fingers, make right.
我只是个愚蠢的牧羊人
I just a stupid goat herder
要是我早知道你没有作为 要害死凯金的话
but I cog you're killin' Catkin by not actin',
我就该让你上了那座桥
just... by lettin' you up on that bridge,
被科纳族吃掉
you Kona meat.
如果躺在那备受煎熬的是先知呢
If a Prescient be layin', with poison meltin' her heart n'lungs?
如果是你的孩子呢
If it be your kin?
先知的生命就比谷民的更值钱吗
Why the Precient's life worth more than a Valleysman?!
我带你去毛娜索尔
I'll take you to Mauna Sol.
我认识路
I know the way!
只要你救下凯金
If you save Catkin,
就算是恶魔之门
I will guide you to the Devil's door,
我也会带你去
if that's where you wanna go.
虽然我还不舍得忘掉过去
While the past may call to us with the enchantment of a siren,
但我觉得
better, I believed,
还是按弟弟的安排走更好
to stay the course set by dear brother Den.
在这里签字
Just sign right here.
明天  一切将重新  重新  重新开始
Tomorrow, life could begin afresh, afresh, afresh.
这边请
This way.
来
Come.
欢迎进入基本作息训练
Welcome to Habitat Basic Training.
启动安保程序
Security activate.
载入纹理
Designating texture.
那是老首尔
That's old Seoul.
要是潮汐以现在的速度继续上涨
If the tides keep rising at their present rate,
新首尔在一百年后也会沉入水底
Neo-Seoul will also be under water in a hundred years.
食物在这里
Your food is in here.
不是你习惯吃的那种
It's not what you're used to,
不过我觉得你会喜欢的
but I think you will like it.
这是你的床
This is your bed...
这些是你的衣服
These are your clothes.
我的  可这些是...纯种人的衣服
Mine? But these are... Pureblood clothes.
不  是你的衣服
No. They are yours.
你知道他是联盟的人吗
Did you know he was Union?
不知道  就算知道也无所谓
No, but it wouldn't have mattered.
为什么
Why not?
因为
Because...
那是第一次有纯种人对我表示善意
It was the first time a Pureblood had showed me kindness.
妈妈
Mama...
我饿了
I hungry.
喜欢吗
Do you like them?
你真美
You look lovely.
这里
Here...
来
Come here.
这是用来播放视频的  不过芯片坏了
Now, this used to play Vidis, but the chip is corrupted.
只会循环播放一段
Stuck in a loop,
我把内容提取出来 找回了剩下的部分
so I digit it and found the rest of it.
剩下的部分
The rest of it?
《蒂莫西·卡文迪许受难记》
你他妈的在我房间里干吗
...the bloody hell are you doing in my room?
钥匙  随身听
Keys... go walkies,
要把这些交给裘德小姐保管好吗
let's give these to Miss Judd for safekeeping, shall we?
别碰我的东西  你这疯母牛
Leave my things alone, you pilvering cow.
你是新来的
Cause you're new,
我就不让你吃肥皂粉了
I shall not make you eat soap powder, this time...
先警告一次
You're warned.
在我们这里 我不能容忍任何冒犯的语言
I cannot stand for offensive language in our arrays,
任何人都不可以
not from anyone.
我从不吓唬人  卡文迪许先生  从不
And I never make idle threats, Mr. Cavendish. Never.
好像我喜欢跟你说话似的  你这个小偷
I'll talk to you as I ruddy will like, you thief!
让我吃肥皂粉  我倒想看看你有什么本事
Make me eat soap powder? I'd like to see you try.
见鬼
Ooh! Ooh, bloody hell!
一开始就这么扫兴
A disappointing start.
难道这是变态虐待旅馆吗
Is this some sort of kinky S&M hotel?
我是诺克斯护士  别惹我
I am nurse Noakes, you do not wish to cross me.
很抱歉让你久等了  你是...
I am so sorry to keep you waiting. Uh, I know it's a Miss...
雷
Rey.
路易莎·雷  《望远镜》杂志的
Luisa Rey, Spyglass magazine.
对  对
Right, right.
路易莎  这是乔·纳皮尔
Luisa, this is Joe Napier,
他是我们的安全主管
he's our security chief.
我很惊讶你会来采访
I was surprised to get your query.
别误会 你们杂志是很活跃  就是
I mean, don't get me wrong, it-it is a feisty magazine, but...
有任何需要  请别客气
Anything you need, sir, just let me know.
好的  这里没问题了  多谢
We'll do. Guys, I'm good, thank you very much.
谢谢  回见了
Thank you, see you.
我们的主编想要加一点爆料
Our editor's trying to spice things up a little bit,
他说公众需要更多实质性的内容  所以
he says the public wants more substance, so...
也许只是一时的狂热
Probably just a fad.
跟我来  从鸡场开始吧
Come on, follow me, let's start you with the Chicken Ranch.
大脑壳们待的地方
That is where we keep the Eggheads.
早啊  卡文迪许先生  今早感觉不错吧
Hello, Mr. Cavendish, feeling super this morning?
才怪  我昨晚入住的时候
No. I checked in last night,
还以为震蛋屋是一家旅馆
believing that Aurora House was a hotel.
我弟弟替我预定的
My brother made the booking you see,
是他的恶作剧吧
his idea of a practical joke.
不过
But listen,
还有个更大的问题
you have a bigger problem closer to home.
有个自称诺克斯的疯女人
There's some demented bitch calling herself Noakes,
在这里胡闹  假扮成女仆
rampaging about the place, impersonating a chamber maid.
更重要的是  她打了我
But the point is this: she struck me,
还偷走了我的钥匙
and she stole my keys.
听到了吗  我要我的钥匙  立刻  马上
Right? I'll need those keys back, straight away.
震蛋屋现在是你的家了
Aurora House is your home now,
卡文迪许先生  你的签名
Mr. Cavendish. Your signature
-授权我们使用  -签名
- authorizes us to apply... - Signature?
你昨晚签过的监护文件
The custody document you signed last night.
你的住宿文件
Your residency papers.
不不不  那是旅馆的入住登记
Oh no, no, no. That was the hotel register.
无所谓了  只是形式罢了  不是吗
Ah, never mind, it's all academic, huh?
这回我可有故事讲了
This is gonna make a hell of a diner party story.
大部分客人在第一天早上 都想回去
Most of our guests get cold feet on their first mornings.
请把钥匙还给我
My keys, please.
-房客们是不能  -我不是该死的房客
- Residents are not... - I'm not a ruddy resident!
你会发现在震蛋屋乱发脾气是无济于事的
You'll find temper tantrums won't help you at Aurora House!
你违背了该死的
You're breaking the... ruddy...
监禁法案  还是什么鬼东西
acting... conservation act, or some ruddy thing,
我不会向暴力犯罪行为屈服
and I will not be subjugated to a criminal abuse.
I will not be subjugated to criminal abuse.
窗外
Outside,
硕大的雪花一片片落在屋顶上
fat snow flakes are falling on slate roofs.
亚历山大•索尔仁尼琴  诺贝尔文学奖作家
就像索尔仁尼琴在付蒙特劳动
Like Solzhenitsyn laboring in Vermont,
在流放中我该努力工作
I shall beaver away in exile.
和索尔仁尼琴不同的是  我并不孤单
Unlike Solzhenitsyn, I shan't be alone.
要去什么地方吗
Off somewhere?
当然了  去现实世界
You bet I am. To the land of the living.
《绿色食品》 1973年的美国科幻电影
绿色食品是人做的
Soylent Green is people.
Soylent Green is made of people!
喂  回来
Oy! Get back here, you!
离我远点  不然我就在警察局的报告中
You keep away from me, or I'll be forced to name you,
把你写成共犯
in the police report, as an accomplice.
我没空跟你胡闹
I have better things to do than this.
那别闹啊  你这个该死的狗杂
Then go, pit and do them, you bloody sucker son of...
够了
Right!
放开你的手  你这个该死的
God, you take hands off me, you ruddy bloody...
只要给人民一些东西
You can maintain power over people,
就可以一直统治他们
as long as you give them something.
夺走某个人的一切
Rob a man of everything,
会失去对那个人的控制
and that man will no longer be in your power.
亚历山大·索尔仁尼琴
亚历山大·索尔仁尼琴 20世纪哲学家全集
Alexander Solzhenitsyn, 20th century philosopher complete works,
统一体的禁书
banned by Unanimity.
你怎么知道他的
How do you know about him?
海柱告诉我的
Hae-Ju.
亚历山大·索尔仁尼琴
不过
But...
-张长官  -叫我海柱就好了
- Sir Zheng. - Please, you must call me Hae-Ju.
海柱
Hae-Ju...
我这样是要没命的
Fabricants can be excised for this...
对啊  生存就是需要勇气的
Well, survival often demands some courage.
知识是面镜子
Knowledge is a mirror,
这是我人生中第一次
and for the first time in my life,
有机会看到自己的过去
I was allowed to see who I was,
还有未来
and who I might become.
去打扫船头
Go clean the head.
早上好  船长
Good morning, captain.
胆小鬼 要是你滚开的话 早上就更美好了
You can help it remain so, old quail cock, by buggering off.
恐怕我做不到
I'm afraid I can't do it, sir.
不然的话 我就没法告诉你我在房间里发现了
If I was, i would be unable to inform you of the stow-away
-偷渡客了  -偷渡客
- that I have discovered in my... - Stow-away?
我向你保证  这个莫里奥里人是走投无路了
I assure you that this Moriori had no choice.
刚才他发誓 说自己是一流的水手
Now he has sworn to me that he is a first class,
要是给他一个机会的话
able bodied seaman,
他可以凭本事挣旅费
capable of earning passage if only given a chance.
偷渡就是偷渡
A stow-away is a stow-away,
就算他能下金蛋也是偷渡
even if he shits silver nuggets.
他向你解释过什么吗
Did he ever explain anything to you?
他告诉我他们的目的
He told me their goal
是创造有自由意志的人造人
was the creation of a free willed Fabricant.
育娜失败了
Yoona had failed.
我是他们最后的希望
I was their last hope.
不得不说要是所有的女记者都像你一样
I have to say if all lady journalists look like you,
我可能就支持妇女解放运动了
I might start to take this, uh, women's lib thing more seriously.
当然欢迎您的支持
Well, I'm sure they can use your sort.
很好
Nice.
好了  你稍等一下
Okay, uh, you wait here
我去找个机灵点的家伙
and I will go find someone smarter who can, uh,
让他帮你解答一些细节问题
walk you through the details of some of your questions.
好的
Right.
卢夫斯·思科史密斯博士
好吧
Okay...
老爸会怎么做
What would Dad do?
谁他妈的这么晚打电话
Who the bloody hell is this?
你知道现在几点了吗
Have you any idea what time it is?
-丹尼  是我  蒂姆  -蒂姆
- Denny, it's me, Tim. - Timothee?
你在哪儿
Where are you?
你应该很清楚我在哪里
Ah, I think you ruddy know about where I am.
房客是不允许打电话的
But residents are denied access to phones.
有人偷带电话进去吗
Someone smuggled one in?
什么  你怎么知道这些规定的
What, you know the rules?
因为是我帮他们起草的
I helped write them, Timmy.
十二年前开始  我就成为震蛋屋的主要股东
I have been a principal investor in Aurora House for twelve years,
没想到居然这么赚钱
it's incredibly lucrative.
你想不到
You can't believe
人们愿意花多少钱把父母关起来
what people would pay to lock-out their parents.
丹  你已经找够乐子了吧
Look, Den, you've had your fun,
我觉得游戏 你玩够了吧
I think it's high time you put an end to this little game of yours.
不不不  蒂姆  我的游戏才刚开始
No, no, no, Timmy. My fun has just begun.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我是你哥哥  你为什么要这样对我
I am your brother, why are you doing this to me?
我觉得问题应该是
I think the better question is-would be,
你干过什么才遭此报应
what have you done to deserve this?
你是什么意思
I don't know what you mean.
得了吧  你真淘气  别侮辱我了
Oh come, naughty old brother, don't insult me.
你以为我不知道你和乔洁特的事吗
You can't think that I didn't know about you and Georgette!
乔洁特
Georgette?
丹...
Look, Den...
我没想伤害你
I didn't mean to hurt you.
现在忏悔晚了  蒂姆
I'm afraid your penance has come due, Timbo,
该赎罪了
it's time to account for your crimes.
丹...
Den...
我...我很抱歉
I'm... I'm so, so sorry.
不不不  没必要道歉
No no no, there's no need to apologize.
流放你就是最好的赎罪
Your exile is more than enough reparation.
你要是看到了诺克斯护士拿着扫帚
Oh, I do have my fingers crossed for a scenario involving you,
不要忘了我正在这边 真心为你祈祷
nurse Noakes and a broom handle.
祝你好运  蒂姆  再见
Cherry up, Timmy. Bye bye now.
他向你问好
He sends his love.
我想问问你被捕那晚的情况
I would like to ask about the night of your arrest.
我记得  我听着他的心跳
I remember... listening to his heart beat.
你的心脏比我们的跳得缓慢的多
Your heart beats much slower than ours.
那声音里有种温情
There is a gentleness to the sound.
我感觉很舒服
I find it... comforting.
维维安  几点了
Vyvyan, what time is it?
不知道  管它呢
I don't know. Who cares...
我刚才听到了一段旋律  用小提琴的
I've heard a melody, boy. For violin.
快点
Quick...
找支笔
Find-find a pen.
我在梦中听到的
I heard it in a dream.
那是个噩梦般的咖啡店
It was in a nightmarish café...
模糊而明亮的灯光  地下室  没有出口
Blurry, bright lights, but underground and no way out.
女服务员们
And the waitresses...
都长着同一张脸
they all had the same face.
那里播放着音乐
There was music played,
和我一生中听到的音乐都不同
not like any music I've ever heard in my life.
开头是
It began...
等一下
Wait...
刚才还记得一清二楚
It was so clear a minute ago.
帮帮我  罗伯特  它要溜走了
Help me, Robert, help me. It's slipping away!
我想不起来了
I've lost it.
你会想起来的
It'll come to you, sir.
你放弃寻找的时候  它却找上了你
The minute you stop trying to find it, it will find you.
你太天真了  罗伯特
You are naive, Robert.
一点也不
I am anything but.
我们之间的鸿沟很深
There is a gulf between these chairs.
我们的追求是一样的
What you want is no different from what I want.
哪有什么鸿沟
The gulf is an illusion.
我该如何描述那晚  思科史密斯
How do I describe that night, Sixsmith...
维维安和我的共鸣  超越了语言
What had happened between Vyvyvan and I transcended language.
那从他的眼中涌出
It was music that poured from his eyes,
从他的唇间低吟而出的乐曲
and breathed from his lips.
比我听过的任何音乐都美妙
Music as beautiful as any I have ever heard.
你  你在干什么
What-what are you doing in here?
他们找到我们了
They found us.
我不会放手  看着我
I'll be with you the whole way, now focus on me.
跟我走
Stay with me.
就在这里  我不会放手的
Right here. I won't let you go.
-尤因先生  -没...没事的
- Mr. Ewing. - It-It's alright.
我和船长谈过了  他会听你说的
I-I talked to the captain, he'll hear your case.
你叫什么  小伙子
What's your name, boy?
奥图阿  先生
Autua, sir.
这位一点不懂航海的基督徒
This Christian gentleman who knows nothing about ships,
说你是一流的水手
tells me that you're a first-class sailor.
来放下主帆  小子
Very well, let's see you'd lower the main top, son.
罗德里克先生  我的瓶子空了
Mr. Roderick, my bottle is empty.
波海威  准备好我的家伙
Boerhaave, ready my piece.
什么  你答应过我的  船长
What? Sir, you... gave me your word, Captain.
求你了  不要这么做
P-Please, you can't do this.
别在我的船上对我指手画脚
Nobody tells me what I can and cannot do on my own ship.
而且还是为了一个偷渡的黑鬼
Specially when it concerns nigger stow-away.
船长  看啊  他脚趾上有鱼钩
Captain look! He's got fish-hooks for toes.
波海威  别脏了我的甲板
Boerhaave, you don't make a mess of my deck.
不要
No.
海柱
Hae-Ju...
船长  求你了
Captain, please...
要是你能听我说  我...
Look, if you can just hear me, I'm...
这黑鬼水性不错
The darkie's salt as I am.
波海威先生
Mr. Boerhaave!
看样子我们又多了一位船员
It appears we have an addition to our crew.
盯住他别偷懒
Make sure he earns his keep.
胡克先生
Mr. Hooks.
找到她了  在化学实验室里
I found her. She was in the chem labs,
她在找卫生间
looking for the bathroom.
是吗  好的  那么
Ah? Well, perfect, then, uh,
干脆你来接手吧  萨克斯
why don't you take over from here, Sachs,
向雷小姐介绍一下我们的小组织
you know, introduce our little tribe, and uh...
带她参观一下大楼
and guide Ms. Rey through the... through the tower.
有意思的是  我本来不该在这里
The funny thing is, I am not even supposed to be here.
我本来应该在首尔
I was meant to be in Seoul,
不过因为空管罢工 航班延误了
but the air traffic controller strike put everything up,
我今晚才走
so now I'm on the... time jumper tonight.
你是否觉得全世界都在跟你作对
Did you ever think that the universe was against you?
一向如此
All the time.
介意吗
You mind?
不介意
I'm cool.
你看起来有点紧张  伊萨克
You seem nervous, Isaac.
-我让你感到紧张吗  -没有
- Do I make you nervous? - No.
实际上恰好相反
Actually, just the opposite.
你会告诉我为什么掩护我吗
Will you gonna tell me why you covered for me?
自由  我们的文明发出的无病呻吟
Freedom. The fatuous jingle of our civilization.
只有那些被剥夺自由的人
But only those deprived of it
才能对它略知一二
have the barest inkling of what it really is.
该怎么处置你有些争议
There's much disagreement on what should be done with you.
统治阶层想要以异类的罪名处你安乐死
The Corprocrats want you euthanased as a deviant,
制造局要求对你进行一段时间的研究
the Manufacturer is demanding a period of study,
心理学家则迫切要求
the Pyschogenomicists are
对你的大脑进行解剖
screaming for an immediate cerebral vivisection.
然而  你的案例是政治问题
However, the problem you create is a political one.
也就是说归我管
Which means you are my problem.
有意思  想象一下
I find it intriguing to imagine that beneath this...
精心设计的外表下面
perfectly engineered features,
藏着怎样的思想  能使整个统一体恐慌
are thoughts that terrify the whole of Unanimity.
我不怕这些思想  因为我敢于直面事实
I'm not afraid of such thoughts, because I do not fear the truth.
这个世界是有秩序的  人造人
There's a natural order to this world, fabricant.
这秩序是必须要遵守的
And the truth is this order must be protected.
通知档案保管员  准备剔除
Inform the Archivist, prepare for excisement.
-遵命  长官  -长官
- Yes sir. - Sir...
能告诉我张海柱怎么样了吗
Can you tell me what happened to Hae-Ju Zheng?
据说死了
Killed, I was told.
这些宴会啊  活动啊  亚当
All this feast and excitements, really Adam, it's...
太累人了  你需要休息
all too much, you'll need to rest.
我曾经...
I had...
有一个女朋友
a girlfriend once,
卡洛斯·卡司纳达  秘鲁裔美国作家
她一直想让我看卡洛斯·卡司纳达的书
she kept trying to get me to read Carlos Castenada.
-你读过吗  -读过
- You ever read any of that stuff? - Oh yeah.
但我俩是没可能的
But the relationship was doomed.
她只要一提
Every time she brought up a new...
她那套因果报应的理论
karma, that sort of stuff,
我就禁不住想笑
I-I couldn't stop myself from laughing.
但是 我却没法解释
And yet i can't explain
我知道打开那扇门之后的报应
that I knew when I opened that door...
他们销毁了报告的大部分副本
They destroyed most of the copies of the report.
大部分
Most?
两难了  对吗
There's no good choice here, is there?
如果帮你  我会失去工作 甚至更糟
If I help you, I close my job or worse,
如果不帮  会有很多人...
If I don't, a lot of people...
难以想象的可怕
And it will be worse than worse.
你必须去做
You have to do
你不能不做的事
whatever you can't not do.
有什么东西追杀你吗  扎克里
Someone preying on you, Zachry?
你真的不怕在山顶遇到老乔治吗
You really ain't fear about meeting Old Georgie on the summit?
比起魔鬼我更担心天气
I'm more scare some about the weather than in the Devil.
你说他不存在
You cog he's real?
如果不是老乔治  是谁造成了大衰落
Who tripped the Fall, if not Old Georgie?
要听真相吗
True-true?
我们的先人
The Old Uns.
这话毫无根据
That's just a rope of smoke.
先人们拥有智慧
Old Uns got the Smart.
他们能妙手回春  掌控生命
They mastered sick and seeds,
他们能创造奇迹  翱翔天际
they make miracles and fly across the sky.
没错  这是事实  但事实不止如此
True. All true. But they got something else.
他们贪得无厌
A hunger in their hearts,
这种贪欲比科技更可怕
a hunger that's stronger than all their Smart.
贪欲  贪什么
Hunger? For what?
贪得更多
A hunger for more.
爱和恐惧这种信仰
Belief like fear or love
是必须要了解的
is forced to be understood
因为这信仰同相对论
as we understand the theory of relativity,
或是测不准原则一样重要
and principles of uncertainty.
这信仰决定了我们生活的轨迹
Phenomena that determine the course of our lives.
昨天  我的生活是那样
Yesterday, my life was headed in one direction.
今天  却完全变了样
Today, it is headed in another.
昨天的我决不相信  今天的我会这么做
Yesterday, I believe I would never have done what I did today.
半衰期  路易莎·雷的秘密  贾维尔·戈麦兹著
有些力量能重置时间和空间
These forces that often remake time and space,
能改变我们脑海中的未来
they can shape and alter who we imagine ourselves to be,
它早在我们出生前就已存在
begin long before we are born,
也会一直存在下去
and continue after we perish.
我们的命运和抉择就如同量子轨迹
Our lives and our choices like quantum trajectories
只有理解此刻  才能得知下一刻
are understood moment to moment
每一次交叉  每一次相遇
at each point of intersection, each encounter,
都预示着新的方向
suggest a new potential direction.
命题
Proposition:
我爱上了路易莎·雷
I have fallen in love with Luisa Rey.
这可能吗  我才刚认识她  但是
Is this possible? I just met her, and yet
却感觉她给我带来了重大的变化
I feel like something important has happened to me.
就是它
That's it.
这是我梦中的旋律
The music from my dream.
这是我来你房间那晚  我梦里的曲子
This is from my dream, that night I came to your room.
我脑海中的旋律  不知怎么传给了你
This is the music I heard in my head, somehow I gave it to you.
这是我这几周创作的
I've been working on this piece for weeks now.
应该是你睡梦中听到  融入梦境了吧
I suspect you heard it, and incorporated it into your dream.
我把它命名为《云图六重奏》
I call it the Cloud Atlas Sextet.
这显然是我们两个合作的
This is obviously the result of our collaboration.
我相信  这首曲子
The Atlas, I believe,
是我这一生最有价值的事
is the only thing I've done in my life that is of value.
但我知道  如果没有遇见你
But I know I could not have written it,
我不可能写出它
if I hadn't met you.
有一整段乐章
There are whole movements
都是我想着我们俩写出来的
in the Atlas that I've read imagining us,
想象我们在不同的年代以不同的身份邂逅
meeting again and again, in different lives and different ages.
没错
Yes.
如此重要的事物
Something as important as
不能说什么是你的  或是我的
this cannot be described as "Yours" Or "Mine",
这是我们的
it is "Ours".
我也是这么想的  维维安
That this is exactly how I feel, Vyvyan.
对不起  我...
I'm sorry, I...
-我以为...-你以为  你以为什么
- I thought... - You thought? You thought what?
你以为我会跟你这只
That I might fancy a little
小花蝴蝶来电吗
buggering from a fine young dandy like yourself?
我去打包  明早就离开
I pack my bag, and be gone by morning.
你不能走
You'll do no such thing,
没有我的允许你不能离开
you'll leave only when I say you can leave.
你要继续创作维维安·艾瑞斯的《云图》
You will continue working on Vyvyan Ayrs' Cloud Atlas.
等你把它写完  我再决定你的去留
When it is finished, then I will decide what you do with you.
你没权力把我关在这里  我要走了
You can't keep me here! I'm leaving!
你自己去创作吧
Good luck with your composing.
我敢肯定你这糟老头
I'm sure a sterile old fuck like yourself
还能写出不少没人听的音乐
is still capable of something completely unmemorable.
你最好想清楚  罗伯特  想想名声
I suggest you think about this, Robert. Think about reputation.
我们这社会中名声最重要
Reputation is everything in our society.
你这被剥夺继承权的荡货名声早毁了
Yours, my disinherited reprobate, has expired.
你以为我们这里
Did you not think that we would
是来者不拒  不看背景的吗
inquire about someone living under our roof?
马克拉斯亲笔写的  我引述一下
Mackerras himself wrote, and I quote:
他是个男妓
"He is a prostitute
在凯斯学院他就总和同性恋们私通
whose liaisons with perverts and sodomites
事业和信仰早已被他抛在脑后
were common place in his brief and forgettable career at Caius.
藏好值钱的东西  引述完毕
Lock up the silverware." End of quote.
警告你  要是不经我允许离开
Be warned. Leave here without my consent,
整个音乐圈的人
and all the musical society
都会知道罗伯特·弗洛比舍的恶行
will know of the degenerate Robert Frobisher.
从此以后
After that,
不管你写的曲子多么伟大
even if you compose one of the greatest symphonies ever written,
都没人愿意听
no one will hear it,
因为没有人想和你扯上关系
because no one will want anything to do with you.
我不会再丢下你了
I won't let you go again.
我就知道他会来
I told you he'd come.
有两件事很明确
Two things became clear.
就算自尽
Hanging myself from Edinburgh's flagpole
也好过让那老寄生虫
is preferable to letting that parasite
霸占我的才华
plunder my talent a day longer.
还有我必须完成六重奏
I must complete my sextet.
在这里我无法创作
I can't do it here,
所以今晚我准备逃走
so tonight I plan to make my escape.
请停车接受扫描
Please stand by for vehicle scan.
准许通行
Clearance granted.
所有的越狱都有风险
Any jailbreak's a risky proposition.
一个小闪失
One little cock-up,
那个母老虎就要大发雷霆
and we are dangling at her majesty's pleasure.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
我们可以用代号
We could use code names,
但我肯定是记不住的
but the truth is I'd probably be the first to forget mine.
所以  卡文迪许先生
So, Mr. Cavendish...
我是厄尼·布兰克史密斯
Ernie Blancksmith.
这是米克斯先生  这是我女友维罗妮卡·科斯特罗
This is Mr. Meeks and my girl Veronica Costello.
-敬信任  -敬信任
- To trust. - To trust.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
这只鹦鹉呢
What about the parrot, then?
这种人总爱打小报告
Forever those are likely songbird.
米克斯先生是位值得尊敬的绅士
Mr. Meeks is a fine and honorable gentleman,
他绝不会背叛我们
he would never betray us.
而且  从来没人听他说过别的话
Besides, no one's ever heard him say anything else.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
问题是  老家伙
Question is, old man,
你够不够精明
think you're up to snuff?
请配合统一体的工作
Unanimity requires compliance.
红色安全警报  准备登机
We have a security code Red, prepare to be boarded.
你打算怎么办
What are you going to do?
保持冷静  冷静
Stay calm, stay calm.
结局会很悲惨  你提醒过我
"It will end in tears." You've warned me.
我想我就和亚当·尤因一样绝望
I suppose I'm as hopeless as Adam Ewing,
说不出话来  只能平躺着等待
oblivious towards the unspeakable forms lying and waiting,
对朋友毒害他的事实一无所知
blind to the fact his friend is poisoning him.
请等一下...
Wait, please...
一想到要失去这枚戒指我就很难过
The idea of losing this ring distresses me beyond measure.
别犯傻  亚当
Don't be a silly puff here, Adam,
为了救命取下戒指  你妻子能理解的
I'm sure your wife will set your health above a golden loop.
我见过这病初期的浮肿  一点也不好看
I have seen the onset for dropsy and it is not a pretty sight!
我认识一个出色的西班牙金匠
I know an excellent Spanish goldsmith,
他的手艺棒极了
who works with such alacrity,
你家蒂尔达也许都看不出你摘下过它
that your Tilda may not have to know this was ever removed.
把它给我
Give it to me!
你他妈别碰我的布丁
Get your fucking hands off my pudding!
这不是你的布丁  你个老年痴呆
It's not your pudding, you Alzheimer riddled lout!
你的已经吃完...
You've already eaten...
来这边
Better get in here.
卡文迪许先生
Mr. Cavendish!
这个房间撒发着药臭味
The room stank of bitter medicine.
枪真是有趣  这么有分量
Curiously heavy things, guns.
我到底为什么拿起它
Why did I take it, exactly?
我说不清
Can't say.
是直觉
An intuition.
非常重要的直觉
A sense of significance.
从这一刻起
That from this point on
再也没有回头路
there was no going back.
山顶看起来还在云中  我们没时间了
Just seeing them clouds, we run out of time.
不
Nay.
-我不要系高科技绳子  -不行  你要是掉下来
- Don't need no smart rope. - Yeah. See you fall,
我能拉住你
I catch you.
举起手  快点  出来  下车
Hands in the air. Now! Move it, step off of the vehicle!
下来  下来  快点
Get down. Down, now!
去你的移民鸟语
Fuckin' migrant monkey-talk.
为什么要雇这种滑头
Why do they hire these greasy subs?
否认  长官  确定违法
Negative, sir. Definite illegal.
你控制住他
You turn him from now.
我发现另一生命体
I'm reading a second life form!
-在哪  -车里
- Where? - In the truck.
-去看看  -是的  长官
- Check it out. - Yes, sir.
你踏入了魔鬼的领地
You trodding on the Devil's ground now,
山谷人
Valleysman.
我只说一次  那个外乡人不能去山顶
I'm saying just once. That off-lander ain't getting to the top.
你该放开绳子了
Time for you to let go that rope.
擅闯入者
You trespass
必付代价
you pay the price.
现在  放开绳子
Now drop that rope.
放开绳子
Drop that rope.
-突击员1  进入车内  -收到
- Forcecom 1, entering the truck. - Roger that.
我打开图像
I turn in visual.
-是她  -没问题  对吧
- It's her! - It'll be okay, uh?
遭到袭击  遭到袭击
Fire on me. Fire on me!
你是什么人
Who are you?
张海柱中校
Commander Hae-Ju Zheng.
反抗联盟首席科学官
First science officer of the Union rebellion.
你为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
因为我相信你有改变世界的力量
Because I believe you have the power to change this world.
放开绳子  松开绳子
Drop that rope. Let go that rope.
双手流血勿松手
"Hands are bleeding, can't let go"
Hands are bleeding. Can't let go.
谢谢你  扎克里
Thank you Zachry.
你救了我两次了
You saved me twice, ain't ya?
你掉下来  我拉住你
You fall, I catch you.
杀伤性武器确认
Excessive force confirmed.
阻止他们  快阻止他们
Stop them. Stop them now.
你在干什么  孩子  没听懂我的话吗
What are you doing, boy? I thought I made myself clear.
-我要走了  你请便吧  -很好  弗洛比舍
- Do what you want. I'm leaving! - Fine, Frobisher...
走吧  但留下这个
Go, but I take this.
-把它给我  -这是我的
- Give that to me. - It's mine!
我警告你
I'm warning you!
考虑到我们现在的关系
Under the conditions of this relationship,
这是我的合法权利
I'm certain that I'm in my legal rights.
把它给我  把它给我
Give it to me. Give it to me,
不然我现在就杀了你  我发誓
or I swear to God I will kill you as you stand!
拜托  你是个懦夫
Please you're a coward.
-我会开枪的  -你不会的
- I'll do it. - You won't pull that trigger.
你这种人永远不会
Your kind never does.
亚当·尤因太平洋日记
没事的  没事的
Yes. Yes, well...
今天感觉如何  亚当
How-how fares our worm today, Adam?
恐怕我快撑不住了
I'm afraid it has taken the best of me.
不不不  胡说  胡说
Oh no no no. Nonsense. Nonsense.
你不能放弃  想想你美丽的妻子
You mustn't give up. You must think of your beautiful wife.
想想蒂尔达
You must think of Tilda.
他们被困在下面  我们追上了
They're trapped in the downway. We've got them.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
快来  快点进去
Come on. Come on, get in there.
不  死人从来都不安分
Nay, the dead never stay dead.
仔细聆听  他们一直喋喋不休
Open your ears, and they'll never stop a yibberin'.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
大衰落之前
Before the Fall,
先人们在太空  在群星间
Old Uns built dwellins,
建造了很多定居地
beyond the sky, among the stars,
这里是连通两地的枢纽
this place joined here with there.
星美
Sonmi.
是她
It is she.
先人也像山谷人一样向星美祈祷吗
The Old Uns pray to Sonmi same as Valleysmen?
不  不完全一样
Nay, not exactly same.
跟紧点  人造人在这里常被抓走
Stay close. Fabricants get snatched here.
-很安全  -谢谢
- All clear. - Thank you.
不客气  我们是伙伴
No sweat, we're partners.
但你得告诉发生了什么
But you got to tell me what's happening.
好的  等我换掉这些衣服  报过警
Okay, let me take off these clothes, call the cops,
我保证早上全都告诉你
and I promise I tell you everything that happen in the morning.
好的  但希望你能意识到
Okay. But I hope you realize you just said exactly
悬疑故事里的人物被杀前说的话
what every character in any decent mystery says
和你说的一模一样
right before they get killed.
晚安  贾维尔
Good night, Javier.
你刚才的话是什么意思  那个...
What'd you mean down there? About...
先人向星美的祈祷和山谷人不太一样
The Old Uns and Valleymen praying to Sonmi not exactly the same?
先人  他们不同
Old men they were different.
不同
Different?
怎么不同
How?
你想知道真相吗
You want the True-true?
这是你住的地方吗
This is where you live?
这是联盟诞生的地方
This is where Union was born.
星美不是神
Sonmi was no God.
她几百年前就死了
She died hundreds of years ago
在一个遥远的半岛  现在那里已是死地
on a faraway peninsula, deadlanded now.
什么
What?
我知道山谷人的信仰
I cog Valleysmen's beliefs,
我知道女祭司教导你们星美是神迹
I know Abbess teach you Sonmi was a miracle,
她是智慧之神达尔文的孩子
birthed of Darwin god of Smart,
但这不是真相
but ain't the True-true.
她的生活很悲惨  充满了背叛
Her life was sad and judased,
她为了改变先人的思想而献身
she died trying to change the Old-Uns thinking.
说谎  全是谎言
Lies. Nothing but lying.
不  不  你在说谎
Nay, nay you, you're lying.
我们不朽生命的天性在于...
The nature of our immortal lives is in the...
星美
Sonmi?
她临死前  说出了自己的所作所为
Before she died, she spoke of her acts and deeding.
她的话语能拯救心灵
Her words are heart saving blessing,
提醒着我什么才是真实
reminding me what's the True-true.
你还要听多久
How long you listen to this?!
还要傻站这里多久
How long you just stand there,
纵容这个陌生人
and let a stranger keep
反复践踏你的信仰
fugging your beliefs up n' down, in n' out!
我们的生命并不属于我们自己
Our lives do not belong to us,
从出生到死亡  我们都与他人紧密相连
from womb to tomb, we're bound to others.
扎克里
Zachry.
你还好吧
You alright?
你继续
Finish your session...
如果我想杀你  你早就死了
If I wanted to kill you, you'd be dead.
我不会伤害你  我只是想谈谈
I'm not gonna hurt you. I just want to talk.
冷静  好吗
Be cool. Alright.
如果我想杀你  你也已经死了
And if I wanted to kill you, you'd be dead already.
有你这么搭讪的吗
How's it feel, uh? Good conversation start, isn't it?
你是莱斯特·雷的女儿  绝对没错
You are Lester Rey's daughter, that's for goddamn sure.
-你认识我父亲  -朝鲜战争时
- You knew my father? - Korean War.
我在2-1排
I was in the two-one.
最边上那个是我  在你爸旁边
That's me on the end, next to your dad.
星球画报  记者拯救整个排
炮弹在我身边爆炸  几乎把我炸飞
Mortar landed so close it could have dropped out of my ass.
要不是你父亲  我不可能有今天
If your father hadn't done what he did, I wouldn't be here.
我也是啊
Guess that makes two of us.
你不愿放开绳子
You ain't let go that rope
因为你看上了这个邪恶的小妞
cause you are lusting for that darkly, sweet meat.
现在我明白了
I cog it all, now.
这个椰子肤色的婊子  带着狡猾的面具
This whore, with her cokeynut skin, and her slywise mask,
微笑着骗取你的信任
smiling and worming her way into your trust
让你带她到这来
so you bring her here,
她在追寻什么
scaving and sivving for what?
探求什么  笨蛋
For what, fool?
他们想要这个岛  先知想占领这里
They want the island. The Prescients want it all.
你为了一个妞出卖了你的同族
You judasing your kin for a piece of ass.
她不是你的同伴  你们连肤色都不同
She ain't your tribe, she ain't even your color,
她无视你们的传说和习俗
she just about ignoring all your yarns and ways,
滔滔不绝地编造她的谎言
spinning and spouting her whoahsomse lies,
你却轻信于她  你真该死
and you lap it up, you dammit!
-那不是真的  -是吗  那就阻止她
- That ain't truth. - Ain't it? Then do something, stop her!
拿出你的匕首割断她的喉咙
Take your spiker and slit her throat!
保护你的族人  你的妹妹还有凯特金
Protect your tribe, protect your sister, little Caktin,
杀了她  不然就晚了
kill her now, before it's too late!
他们会杀了你
They will kill you.
-我比你更了解他们  -是吗
- You don't know these people like I do. - Yeah?
如果你只是想跟我说这个
Well if that's all you came to tell me,
那么你来晚了
you're a little bit late.
有人刚把我撞下了天鹅颈桥
Somebody just forced me off the Swannekke bridge.
局面失控了
This is out of control.
你知道是谁干的吗
Do you know who did it?
自称比尔·斯莫克的雇佣杀手
The contractor calls himself Bill Smoke.
-而且...  -什么
- And... - What?
他杀了萨克斯
He got Sachs.
伊萨克
Isaac?
他的飞机上有炸弹
A bomb on his plane.
媒体在谴责巴勒斯坦解放组织
The press is blaming the PLO.
他是个威胁  就像思科史密斯  你也是
He was a threat. Like Sixsmith, like you.
放他们过去
Bring them through.
星美451  很荣幸见到你
Sonmi 451, I'm most honored to meet you.
我是安可·阿皮斯将军  联盟的领导人
I am General An-Cor Apis, leader of Union.
谁雇的他们
Who is paying them?
雇我的人
The same guy that pays me.
劳埃德·胡克
Lloyd Hooks?
休斯·派克咨询公司
Hughes & Pikes Consulting.
我听说过他们
I've heard of them.
他们为石油公司游说
They're lobbiers for oil companies.
为什么大型石油公司
Why would big oil
要雇劳埃德·胡克经营核反应堆
hire Lloyd Hooks to run a nuclear reactor?
你这表情和你父亲的一样
You get that same look your father used to get.
我就说吧
You see I told you.
胡克不希望别人发现报告
Hooks doesn't want the report discovered,
因为他不希望反应堆修好
because he doesn't want the reactor fixed.
他想让它失败
He wants it to fail.
这关系到国家能源的未来
This is about the future of energy in this country.
他们希望发生爆炸  混乱和死亡
They want the explosion. The chaos and carnage.
死的人越多越好
The more deaths, the better.
我不明白  你的话像黄蜂一样刺痛着我
Can't cog of thing, words and worries are like a wasp's nest,
让我心烦意乱
poked and prodded by you.
你闯入我们的生活  反复念叨真相
You come elbowing in our life, yibbering about the True-true,
却又不愿意全说出来
and never telling the whole true.
我要知道你到底在干什么
I need to cog what you doing!
我告诉过你  我是来请求帮助的
I told you. I come to send a plea of help.
帮助  为什么
Help, why?
为了夺取我的家园  杀害并奴役我们吗
To steal our land? To kill n' slave us all?!
你想要什么
What do you want?!
先知的日子不多了  扎克里  像凯金一样
Prescients are dying, Zachry. Just like Catkin.
这个世界毒害着我和我的族人
This world poison me and all my kin.
我们很无助  再不想办法就会失去家园
We get no help, ain't no home if I don' find a way.
我说的是真的  我们要灭亡了
I say the truesome. We not survive.
我们要灭亡了
We not survive.
艾瑞斯派人来追踪我了
Ayrs has the dogs after me.
子弹虽然击中了他  却只伤到了胃
The bullet passed through, killing little more than his appetite,
他想要血债血偿  我不得不付出代价
and he's out for blood. I'll have to pay the piper.
-我应该报警  -没用的
- I should call the cops. - It won't help.
我怎么知道你不是在骗我
How do I know you're not lying to me?
斯莫克一发现我在跟你合作
Smoke will be coming for me,
马上就会来找我
as soon as he figures out I'm with you.
我们需要那份报告
We need that report.
没有它我保不了你多久
I can't protect you for long without it.
-阿皮斯将军...  -亲爱的
- General Apis... - You, my dear,
你证明了我们的努力没有白费
are proof our efforts were not in vain.
但我只是个服务员
But I'm just a dinery server.
我生来就没法改变现实
I was not genomed to alter reality.
革命家也都不是天生的
No revolutionary ever was.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我没法满足你的要求
I cannot do what you're asking.
这对任何人都是个艰难的选择
It would be a difficult choice for anyone.
但是  在你最终决定前
But, before you call your decision final,
我想让你看点东西
there is one last thing I would like you to see,
让你了解一下我们在抗争什么
in order to fully understand what we are fighting for.
祈求好运吧
Cross your fingers n' toes.
如果你的愿望实现
If your pray' be answered,
先知们再也不会来山谷了吗
nay Prescients never return to the Valley again?
想和我们一起走的  我们热烈欢迎
Those wishing to come with us, they're welcome.
山谷是我的家
The Valley is my home.
你没事吧
Are you alright?
我知道这是禁止的
I know it is forbidden.
思科史密斯  每天清晨我登上苏格兰纪念碑
Sixsmith. I climb the steps of the Scot monument every morning.
一切就变得明朗起来
And all becomes clear.
真希望能让你看到这光明
Wish I could make you see this brightness.
别担心  一切都好
Don't worry, all is well.
一切都好到不能再好
All is so perfectly, damnably well.
我现在明白了
I understand now,
噪音和音乐之间的界限只是陈规
that boundaries between noise and sound are conventions.
所有界限都是陈规  等着被打破
All boundaries are conventions, waiting to be transcended.
只有敢去想
One may transcend any convention,
才能打破陈规
if only one can first conceive of doing so.
在这样的时刻
Moments like this,
我能清楚地感知到你的心跳
I can feel your heart beating as clearly as I feel my own,
亦知你我的分离只是种幻觉
and I know that separation is an illusion.
我的生命远远超越了自我的局限
My life extends far beyond the limitations of me.
风暴要来了  尤因先生  我们下去吧
Storm is coming, Mr. Ewing. Gonna get you down below.
我他妈不是做慈善的  给我滚  滚蛋
I'm not running a fuckin' charity, out with you! Off you go!!
尤因先生  跟您说句话行吗
Aah, Mr. Ewing! A-a-a word if you may.
这年头世道险恶啊  关于那丑闻
Dangerous times we have here. About that scandal.
据说那法外之徒罗伯特·弗洛比舍竟是个作曲家
They say that ruffian Robert Frobisher is a composer.
你也是个作曲家吧
You're a composer too, aren't you Mr. Ewing?
-你想怎样  -警察原本要搜我的旅馆
- What d'you want? - The constable asked to search my rooms.
我明白你在努力工作
I know how hard... you're working,
所以我告诉他们三楼没人
so I told him there's no one on the third floor.
单为你空出三楼得花不少钱
It costs quite a bit of money to keep an entire floor empty.
我只有这么多
That's all I have.
多漂亮的小马甲啊
What a beautiful... waistcoat.
如果这些信并不重要
If these letters aren't important,
-你干嘛还翻来覆去读  -我不知道
- why do you keep reading them? - I don't know.
我只是  试着去搞清楚罢了
Maybe I'm... just trying to understand something.
搞清楚什么
What?
为什么我们总是犯同样的错误
Why we keep making the same mistakes, over and over.
也许你该去问...梅根
Maybe you should ask... Megan.
-你说什么  -你认识叫梅根的吗
- What? - Do you know a Megan?
那是他的侄女  你从哪儿知道的
That's his niece. How do you know that?
他似乎寄给过她一些东西
Looks like he mailed something to her.
可能用了原来装这些信的信封
Probably used the envelope he was keeping letters in.
拜托  路易莎  写神秘小说的第一准则是
Come on, Luisa. First rule of mystery writing:
一条有用的线索总会带出另一条
a good clue always leads to another clue.
当"蒂莫西·卡文迪许的受难记"
When "The Ghostly Ordeal of Timothy Cavendish"
要被拍成电影时
is turned into a film,
我所设想的男主角
I'm thinking for the role of the hero,
要有劳伦斯·奥利弗的感觉[著名英国男演员]
one part Sir Laurence Olivier
还要有点像迈克尔·凯恩[同上]
with a dash of Michael Caine.
你到底是谁
Who the hell is this?
震蛋屋的康威医生  我替阿沃医生的班
Dr. Conway, Aurora House, I'm covering for Dr. Upward.
-是我妈的事情吗  -是的  霍奇克斯先生
- Ooh, is this about mother? - Yes, it is, Mr. Hotchkiss
你得做好心理准备
I-I'm afraid you must steel yourself,
她可能撑不过今晚了
I don't think that she's gonna last the night.
很不巧  这个时间不太凑巧
Unfortunately, it is an unconvenient time for us,
我们必须现在来吗
do we really need to come right now?
不  当然不用  不过她倒是特别提到你
No no, of course not, but she did ask for you specifically,
她好像对遗嘱不太满意
and she seems quite upset about her last will.
我这就来
I'll be right there.
整个计划就像推倒一串多米诺骨牌
The plan was a series of toppling dominoes,
倒的第一张牌
that had commenced with
就是厄尼告诉诺克斯护士我的死讯
Ernie announcing my death to nurse Noakes.
-我知道  我知道  -嘘
- I know, I know. - Shhh!
行动成功的关键在于  米克斯得闭上嘴
The entire ambush hinged upon the silence of Mr. Meeks.
-我知道  我知道  -嘘
- I know, I know. - Shh!
卡文迪许先生
Mr. Cavendish?
一切都好吗
Everything alright?
-别丢下我  -嘘
- Don't leave me here. - Shh.
卡文迪许先生
Mr. Cavendish?
我就知道没这种好事
I knew it! It was too good to be true!
你这臭婊子
You cantankerous witch!
霍奇克斯先生  你母亲
Mr. Hotchkiss, your mother
是我最好的朋友  请快点
is my dearest friend here. Do please hurry.
那么  再见
And so... adieu!
在法文里的意思是
Which translated literally from the French means
向上帝
"To commend before...
称颂你
God"!
乔·纳皮尔在1号线  胡克先生  他说有急事
I have Joe Napier on Line 1, Mr. Hooks. He said he can't wait.
拜托  乔  我要迟到了  什么事
For God sake, Joe, I am late already. What's up?
那叫雷的记者打来电话
I got a call from that reporter. Rey...
她问起思科史密斯的事情
She was asking about Sixsmith.
我明白了
I see.
你说过她不会纠缠不休的
You said she wasn't gonna be a problem.
有些人就是那么难缠啊  乔
Well, some problems are more resilient than others, Joe.
-该死的钥匙呢  -他没留在钥匙孔里
- Where's the ruddy key? - He didn't leave it in the ignition!
他老婆开的车  在她那儿
His wife was driving, she took it,
那该死的女人拿走了钥匙
the ruddy female took the key in with her!
我的老天爷啊  这下可怎么办
Oh Sweet Saint Ruddy Jude, what do we do now?
看看遮阳板下面有没有
Look! Under the sunflap.
太棒了
Yes!
这是什么玩意儿
What is it?
这不是钥匙  该怎么用它啊
It's not a key, what'd you do with it?
-不是钥匙还能是什么  -那怎么用呢
- What else could it be? - Well, how does it work?
-妈的  -不好了
- Shite! - Oh no!
想点办法  你是天才啊
Well, think of something, you're the genius,
你他娘的可是个天才啊
you're the ruddy, ruddy genius!
我们完蛋了
We're done for.
老天  真不敢相信我要这么做
Oh boy. I can't even believe I'm going to do this.
这东西有用吗  还开着吗  能听到我吗
Is this thing working? I mean is it still on, can you hear me?
继续走别停下
Just keep walking.
我觉得他上钩了
I think he's buying me.
无论如何也别回头看
Whatever you do, don't look back.
滚出我的车
Get out of my car!
使劲按那按钮
Press that button thru!
太好了
Yes! Yeees!
糟糕  是米克斯  他也想来
Oh no, it's Mr. Meeks, he does want to come.
这叫什么事儿啊
Ruddy bloody hell!
我为人人  人人为我吗
All for one and one for all?
看住大门
The gate!
维罗妮卡  帮米克斯开个车门好吗
Veronica, would you unlock the door for Mr. Meeks.
米克斯先生  我们去午夜自驾游呢
Hello Mr. Meeks, we're out for a nighttime drive.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
-全速前进  -好兴奋呀
- Ramming speed! - Oh, how thrilling!
不好啦
Oh, no!
-油门踩到底  卡文迪许  -冲啊
- Foot to the floor, Cavendish! - Here we go!
开始行动
Here we go.
来吧  亚当  大口喝下吧
Come along now, Adam, handsomely does it
病情在反复
Oh, the worm fights back,
黎明前总是最黑暗的
it is always darkest before the dawn.
尤因先生
Mr. Ewing?
尤因先生正在治疗的关键时候
Mr. Ewing is at a critical juncture of his treatment.
是死是活  就看接下来几小时了
The next few hours will determine if he lives or die.
那我留在这里
Then I stay here.
别  别  你不能留下
No, no, no you can't.
我必须留下  尤因先生救过我
I must. Mr. Ewing save my life.
我理应这么做
It my duty.
你给我听好  你这大马猴
Listen to me, you ignorant ape,
尤因先生不用你陪着
Mr. Ewing doesn't want you around him,
说不准就是你传染给他的
you probably infected him to begin with.
他求我说"让那肮脏的黑鬼离我远点"
He begged me, and I quote: "Keep that dirty nigger away from me!"
请你尊重他的意愿
So please kindly respect his wishes!
-他去哪儿了  -我不知道
- Where'd he go? - I don't know.
妈的
Shit!
-为自由干杯  -敬自由
- To freedom. - To freedom.
你们全要吃不了兜着走
You are going to be sorry in ways you cannot even imagine.
乔
Joe!
-这里没有非法移民  -你瞧
- No immigrants here, no immigrants here. - Look,
我不是个警察  我们需要你的帮助
I'm not an inspector. We need your help...
我听不懂你说什么
I don't understand.
我们不想把警察扯进来
We don't want the police to get involved,
有个人想杀我们
but there is a man trying to kill me
我们真的需要你的帮助
and we really need your help.
这里没有苏格兰爷们儿了吗
Are there no true Scotsmen in the house?
这些英格兰杂种
Those there English gerants
要侵犯我神圣的人权
are trampling all over my God-given rights!
这些人归我管
These people are mine.
他们残忍虐待我和我的朋友
They've used me an' my pals most direly,
现在我们需要帮助
and we're in need of a wee bit of assistance!
好的  伙计
All right, pal.
我们不会让你失望的
We'll not gonna let ya down.
你给我小心点  你这个草包
Now you just look here, you grebo
苏格兰蠢货给我滚远些
you can go shag your bloody sporran...
刚进来的两个人往哪边跑了
OK, two people came in here. Which way did they go?
往哪边跑了
Which way did they go?!
闭嘴
Shut up!
闭上你的鸟嘴
Shut the fuck up!
偷渡的蠢货
Stupid fucking wetback.
那是什么呀  尤因
What? What's that, Ewing?
你含糊不清的我可不明白呀
How shall I comprehend when you drool and dribble so?
让我猜猜  你好像在说
Oh, let me hazard a guess, something in the key of
"噢  亨利  你怎么能如此对我"
"Oh Henry, how could you do this to me?
"我们可是朋友啊"  不好意思  你错了
"I thought we were friends?" Oh, unfortunately, you're wrong.
错的和霍洛以及你的蠢岳父一样
Wrong like Horrox and your silly father-in-law.
在这个世界上
There is only one rule
约束着芸芸众生的
that binds all people, one governing principle
从来就只有这么一条规矩
that defines every relationship on God's green earth.
弱肉强食
"The Weak are Meat and the Strong Do Eat."
走那条路
That way.
我告诉过胡克不能信你  乔
I told Hooks you couldn't be trusted, Joe.
下一个就是你死  你这狗崽子
You'll be next, you son of a bitch.
出来混  是要还的
Part of the business.
安心下黄泉吧
Enjoy your retirement.
那狗  是我的  宝贝
Amaba... A este... perro!
还有  别他妈叫我偷渡的
And don't call me a fucking wetback.
你要问我为什么
"Why?" You ask.
很简单  因为我想要你箱子里的金子
It's absurdly simple, there is gold in your trunk, I want it.
就为这我得宰了你
so I've killed you for it.
放开尤因先生  不然我会杀了你
Get away from Mr. Ewing or I kill you!
尤因先生  尤因先生
Mr. Ewing, Mr. Ewing!
得让你吐出...  振作点  尤因先生
Got to flush you with the... Com'on, Mr. Ewing.
什么声音
What was that?
科纳的战吼
Kona war cry.
扎克里
Zachry!
不  星美  不要
Oh no no, Sonmi, no.
扎克里
Zachry!
这就是将军想让我看的吗
This is what the general wanted me to see?
终章的灵感像潮水般涌来  我废寝忘食
The end rushes towards me. Unable to eat or sleep.
像尤因一样  这些尘世琐事只是桎梏
Like Ewing, the mortal coil has become a noose.
而无益于音乐
but rather become music.
她们以为会去往极乐神殿
They believe they're going to Exultation.
但其实不是  对吧
But they are not, are they?
欢迎你  阿凯丝
Welcome, Alcelsium.
请坐
Take a seat.
放松点
Just relax.
我们要取下项圈
This is to remove your collar.
敌人熟睡勿割喉
"Enemy's sleepin', don't slit that throat"
基因工业需要
The genomics industry demands
大量的生物材料来制造培育容器
a huge quantity of biomatter for wombtanks.
更重要的是喂养劳动力
but more importantly, to sustain their engineered labor force.
回收的人造人是廉价的蛋白质来源
Recycled fabricants are a cheap source of protein.
这就是汤食
Soap.
我们吃的是同胞
They feed us to ourselves.
那艘船
That ship...
必须被摧毁
The ship must be destroyed.
没错
Yes.
培育人造人的系统必须关闭
The systems that built them must be turned down.
没错
Yes.
不管生于子宫还是容器
No matter if you are born in a tank or a womb,
我们一样是纯种人
we are all pureblood.
没错
Yes.
我们必须战斗  甚至不惜牺牲
We must all fight... and if necessary, die
来告知世人真相
to teach people the truth.
我们一直期待这一天
This is what we have been waiting for.
完成了
It's done.
天那  过来  凯金
Oh, oh. Here, Catkin. Oh.
我的凯金
Oh, oh. Catkin.
然后你被送往反抗联盟的卫星站
You were then taken to a Union control satellite link.
我把我的启示
I broadcast my revelation to
传达给十二个联邦以及四个外星殖民地
the twelve States and four Off-World colonies.
18分钟后  执法者展开攻击
18 minutes later, the Enforcers attacked.
存在即是被感知
To be is to be perceived.
而要了解自我
And so to know thyself is
也只能通过他人之眼
only possible through the eyes of the other.
生命不朽的真谛
The nature of our immortal lives
在于我们言与行的影响
is in the consequences of our words and deeds,
将会源源不断  永世长存
that go on apportioning themselves throughout all time.
躲起来  躲好
Hide. Hide!
扎克里
Zachary!
你杀了酋长  现在你就是刀下鱼肉
From good chief, now you're meat.
-凯金  -扎克叔叔
- Catkin - Uncle Zach.
感谢星美保佑
Thanks, Sonmi.
不  谢谢你才对
No, thank you.
来吧  尤因先生  再喝一口
Com'on, Mr. Ewing. One more.
盐会清洗你的肠胃
Salt clean out your stomach.
起作用了  尤因先生  加油
It goes. Com'on Mr. Ewing, com'on!
看看我们在哪儿  尤因先生
See where we are, Mr. Ewing?
这是家
Home.
梅根  思科史密斯
Megan Sixsmith?
让他们付出代价
Make them pay.
你就看我的吧
You can count on it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我的叔叔是个科学家
My uncle was a scientist,
但是  他坚信爱情的存在
but... he believed that love was real.
那是一种  自然现象
A kind of... natural phenomenon.
他相信爱情能经受死亡的考验
He believed that love could outlive death.
我如痴如醉地完成了它
Finished it in a frenzy
这把我勾回到我们在剑桥的最后一夜
that reminded me of our last night in Cambridge.
欣赏最后一次看日出  享受最后一根烟
Watched my final sunrise, enjoyed the last cigarette.
我以为那是最完美的景象
Didn't think the view could be anymore perfect,
直到我看到你那顶破呢帽
until I saw that beat-up trilby.
老实说  思科史密斯  虽然你戴着很滑稽
Honestly, Sixsmith. As ridiculous as that thing makes you look,
我却觉得那是世间最美的风景
I don't believe I've ever seen anything more beautiful.
我斗胆一直看着你
Watched you for as long as I dared.
我觉得是上天安排  让我先看到你
I don't believe it was a fluke... that I saw you first.
-好的  -谢谢
- Okay. - Thank you.
船长同意让你随行
Captain say-so take ya with us.
-我想和梅洛内一起走  -走  去哪
- I wanna go with Meronym. - Go... Go where?
先知们和我们遭遇一样  家园不复存在了
Prescients in the same boat as us. Got no home neitherwise.
不  还不一定
Nay, not yet.
你觉得会有人听到你的祷告
You think someone gonna hear your prayer,
然后从天而降吗
come down from the sky?
也许吧
Perhaps...
也许有那么一天
Perhaps one day.
这希望跟跳蚤一样大
One day ain't but a flea o' hope.
对  但跳蚤可是很顽强
Yay, and fleas ain't so easy to rid.
我相信有另一个世界在等着我们  思科史密斯
I believe there is another world waiting for us, Sixsmith.
一个更好的世界
A better world.
我会在那里等你
And I'll be waiting for you there.
有什么能帮你吗  先生
May I help you, sir?
是的  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
我在找我朋友  他来了爱丁...
I'm, I'mlooking for a friend who came to Edin...
我认为死亡并不会持久
I believe we do not stay dead long.
来科西嘉星空下我们的初吻地找我吧
Find me beneath the Corsican stars where we first kissed.
你永远的  R.F
Yours eternally. R.F.
报告说张少校在突袭中身亡了
The report said commander Zheng was killed in the assault.
没错
That is correct.
但你说你爱过他吗
But you say that you loved him?
我爱他
Yes I do.
你是说你依然爱着他吗
Do you mean you are still in love with him?
我是说我将永远爱他
I mean that I will always be.
我们的生命不仅仅属于自己
Our lives are not our own.
从生到死  我们与他人息息相关
From womb to tomb, we're bound to others.
过去和现在
Past and present.
每一次罪孽以及每一次善行
And by each crime and every kindness,
来世终将有报
we birth our future.
在你的启示里
In your revelation,
你谈到了生命在永恒中轮回
you spoke of the consequences of an individual's life
所造成的影响
rippling throughout eternity.
那是否表示你相信有来世
Does this mean that you believe in an afterlife?
在天堂或者地狱
In a heaven or hell?
我相信死亡只是一扇门
I believe death is only a door.
当一扇门关闭  另一扇会开启
When its closes, another opens.
若要我想象天堂
If I care to imagine heaven,
我觉得那就像一扇新开启的门
I would imagine a door opening.
在门后
And behind it,
我会找到  等我的他
I will find him there, waiting for me.
我的爱人
My love.
上帝啊  我太想你了
Oh God, I missed you so much.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
请允许我问最后一个问题
If I may ask one last question...
你当时肯定知道反抗联盟的计划必败
You had to know this Union scheme was doomed to fail.
是的
Yes.
那你为什么还答应要做
And why did you agree to it?
这正是阿皮斯将军要求我去做的
This is what general Apis asked of me.
做什么  被处决吗
What, to be executed?
如果没人知道我  真相也无法大白天下
If I had remained invisible, the truth would stay hidden.
我无法接受
I couldn't allow that.
倘若没人相信你说的事实呢
And what if no one believes this truth?
有人已经相信了
Someone already does.
亚当  老天啊
Adam, good God...
我正在讲述你的惊人旅程呢
I have just been recounting your astonishing adventure.
请一起来吧  拿一把椅子来
Please, join us. Give him a chair.
不了  谢谢你
No no, thank you.
我不能久留
I cannot stay.
你怎么来这里了
What are you doing here?
医生不是说至少卧床三周吗
I thought the doctor said at least three weeks in bed?
没错  但是事不宜迟
He did, but this couldn't wait.
我得私下里和你谈谈  先生
I need to speak with you, sir. Privately.
没问题
Of course.
这是霍洛教士拿来的合同吗
Is that the contract from Reverend Horrox?
-正是  -我可以派个人去取的
- It is indeed. - Well, you know I could have sent a boy.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?!
我的命是一个解放了自己的奴隶救的
I owe my life to a self-freed slave.
这种肮脏的交易
And I cannot, in good conscience
我再也不能昧着良心做下去了
participate in this kind of business any longer.
石油说客因天鹅颈岛丑闻被捕
把这写成书肯定会大卖
This would make such a good book.
来干一杯
I'll drink to that.
窗外  硕大的雪花
Outside, fat snow flakes
一片片落在屋顶上
are falling on slate roofs and granite walls.
就像索尔仁尼琴在付蒙特劳动
Like Solzhenitsyn laboring in Vermont,
在流放中我该努力工作
I shall beaver away in exile.
和索尔仁尼琴不同的是  我并不孤单
Unlike Solzhenitsyn, I shan't be alone.
你这该死的  你要不是我的女婿
Goddamn you, sir, if you were not my daughter's husband...
你好  父亲
Hello, father.
蒂尔达
Tilda?
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我是来道别的
I've come to say goodbye.
道什么别  你要去哪儿
Goodbye? Where are you going?
我们要回东部  和废奴主义者一起奋斗
We're moving back East, to work with the abolitionists.
你说什么
What?
你的脑子被毒药腐蚀了吧
That poison has rotted your brain.
如果真是  那我建议你也来点毒药
Well, if it has, I highly recommend it.
我好久没感觉这么棒了
I've not felt this good in years.
蒂尔达  我禁止你和这疯子去任何地方
Tilda, I forbid you from going anywhere with this mad man.
我一生都在畏惧你  父亲
I've been afraid of you my whole life, father.
这次我要和我丈夫一起走
I'm going with my husband.
亚当
Adam.
听我说
Listen to me...
就算不是为了你  也想想我的外孙
For the sake of my grandson, if not your own...
这个世界是有秩序的
there is a natural order to this world,
那些企图颠覆秩序的人不会善终
And those who try to upend it do not fare well.
这条路行不通的
This movement will never survive.
如果你加入他们  你们全家都会被放逐
If you join them, you and your entire family will be shunned.
好点的话  作为贱民被唾弃和鞭笞
At best, you'll exist as pariah, to be spat on and beaten.
运气坏点  被折磨  私刑处死
At worst, lynched or crucified.
为了什么
And for what?
为了什么啊
For what?
不管做什么  你的努力
No matter what you do, it will never amount to anything more
都只不过像是无垠大海里的一滴水
than a single drop in a limitless ocean.
没有水滴  又哪儿来的大海
What is an ocean... but a multitude of drops?
火要熄灭了
Fire is dyin'.
正好我的故事也讲完了
Just as well, my yarning is done.
别呀  求你啦  爷爷  再讲个故事吧
No, Gran'Pi please! Tell us another story. C'mon, please!
过来这里  你们这些小捣蛋
Come on, come here, you little buggars!
赶紧的  天凉了
Com'on, it's getting cold!
没法子  听奶奶的吧  赶紧回去
Hup n'pe, you heard your Gran'mi, com'on, get on with you.
你喜欢呆外面  是吧爷爷
You like it out here, don't you Gran'pi?
我想是吧  让我回忆起我的山谷
Supposin'... Mind'es me of my Valley.
哪一颗是地球
Which is Earth?
那一颗  闪着蓝光的就是
That'un there, that blue shimmerer.
扶爷爷站起来吧
Now, help ya Gran'pi up.
你会给我们讲
Are you gonna tell us
那艘大飞船和长长的休眠
about the whoahsome ship, and the Big Sleep,
还有好多后来的故事吗
and all the next-next?
你奶奶讲那些讲得比我好多啦
Oh, your Gran'mi tells the next-next way better than me.
你还爱奶奶吗
D'ya still love Gran'mi?
你奶奶是我生命里最美好的意外
Your Gran'mi... is the best thin' that ever happened to me.
来吧  老头子
Come o'er here, Gran'pi.
让我暖暖你那把老骨头
Let me warm them ol' bone.